<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 14:31:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The makings of a strategy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-makings-of-a-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-makings-of-a-strategy/</guid>
      <description>A product process is typically something like Strategy → Discovery → Specification → Build → Delivery.
We on product teams understand most of these, but many companies struggle with “strategy”. It’s often mocked, and often with reason.
What is it for? What makes a good one?
Actionable A PM, a developer, or a designer reading a strategy should think “Yes! I know what to do next.” Product should fall out of a strategy naturally and quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward less injection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/toward-less-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 21:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/toward-less-injection/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a habit that may help to reduce the complexity of your dependency injection tree. Ask yourself: how much of an injected dependency are you actually using?
The conversation goes like this…
I need to inject an HttpContext Great. Why? Because we need to read a cookie. So really….
Ah, OK I only need to inject an HttpRequest Better! But seriously, are you only looking at cookies?
Right, I only ever touch Request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPIs are software</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/kpis-are-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 15:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/kpis-are-software/</guid>
      <description>It’s easy to think of key performance indicators as a task to be tacked on to the end of a project. Rather, KPIs should be understood as a product like any other, and so:
…they need strategy The person responsible for a product’s strategy will have specific hypotheses about what numbers they want to move. Key entities and concepts are described, as they will influence everything that follows.
…they need discovery This is where the PM is responsible for choosing the right KPIs, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time well spent</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/time-well-spent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 15:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/time-well-spent/</guid>
      <description>Critical to developer and company success is the idea of time well spent. Optimistically, the company’s and the dev’s incentives are aligned in this regard.
From the dev’s perspective, time well spent includes:
 Doing valuable, differentiated work Avoiding time-consuming, uninteresting barriers to work Working on things that matter Working on things that ship Showing visible progress Taking on challenges + learning  I’ll translate them into management terms:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decker, for a prettier Twitter</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/decker-for-a-prettier-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 20:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/decker-for-a-prettier-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I made a Chrome extension which makes Twitter.com’s UX more tolerable, called decker. It:
 Widens the content area and removes the columns with “Trends” and “Who to follow”, etc. Resolves (i.e., removes) the t.co redirects. You’ll go directly to the URL in a tweet. Auto-loads new tweets instead of showing you the “N new tweets” bar. Pro tip: if you are scrolled down the page it will not auto-load new tweets, to avoid annoying scroll jumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lore</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/lore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 16:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/lore/</guid>
      <description>Code has a user experience. Our methods have a UX. Our data models have a UX.
The users are our colleagues, current and future. We are always on the lookout for fresh information, even anecdotal, on the success of our users.
A big UX problem is an abundance of lore. Lore is when a developer needs to hear an explanation from an elder before using a piece of code, and in the absence of such storytelling, will have a bad time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of null-free programming</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/principles-of-nullfree-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 19:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/principles-of-nullfree-programming/</guid>
      <description>Nulls are a notorious source of bugs in many programming languages. Here, I sketch out a way to avoid them, using C# for illustration.
To be clear, this post is intended as habits for human programmers; it is specifically not about static analysis or language features.
Principles I submit that we can avoid a large majority of null-related errors if we follow these two principles:
 Passing a null is a programming error Branching on null is a programming error  I think most of our problems trace back to imbuing null with meaning, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining version control for APIs</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/imagining-version-control-for-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/imagining-version-control-for-apis/</guid>
      <description>Versioning is, right now, merely a human label. We have helpful conventions like semver, but one still relies on human judgment as to the definition of a “notable” change.
What if the machine could detect, and perhaps describe, API changes in a meaningful way?
What I imagine is this: a program that examines a program’s API for changes, and describes them. Version control, in other words, of the sort we expect from Git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three ways the new iOS ad blocking hurts Google</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/three-ways-the-new-ios-ad-blocking-hurts-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 14:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/three-ways-the-new-ios-ad-blocking-hurts-google/</guid>
      <description>Apple’s ad blocking API is good for users and bad for Google, in 3 ways:
1: Blocking ads, of course This is the most direct way that Apple’s API is bad for Google: more mobile users can block ads, which are the basis of Google’s business.
(That said, the economics are such that it will not be a linear relationship between “ads blocked” and “$ lost”, due to the incredible wastefulness of the status quo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three outcomes of the adpocalypse</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/three-outcomes-of-the-adpocalypse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 22:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/three-outcomes-of-the-adpocalypse/</guid>
      <description>It appears that Internet advertising is going through a bit of a shakeout. Ad blocking is becoming more pervasive (perhaps 30% of users), and a study by Google indicates that as many as 50% of ad “impressions” are never actually put in front of a human being.
For those that rely on ad revenues in their business, this might seem like a reason for panic. I don’t know if it is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve the median, not the mean</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/improve-the-median-not-the-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 21:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/improve-the-median-not-the-mean/</guid>
      <description>I like seeing Google Fiber prompt incumbent dinosaurs into boosting speeds. It’s great.
But: it doesn’t matter much. I have 10x the bandwidth at work (gigabit) than I do at home. I barely notice it, however, for both technical and perceptual reasons.
In fact, my home internet recently improved 3x from ~30mbps to its current ~100mbps. Maybe videos achieve HD a little more quickly? Maybe?
Point being, I had decent bandwidth for my use cases, and the new bandwidth — which I am intellectually thrilled about — offers diminishing returns of actual utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquidity, open source and security</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/liquidity-open-source-and-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 19:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/liquidity-open-source-and-security/</guid>
      <description>Jeff has a thoughtful post about open source, security and incentives. A few points stood out to me.
Liquidity First, the “all bugs are shallow” idea is a bit idealistic, as he points out. What comes to mind for me is Joel’s Hitting the High Notes. Tens of thousands of average developers will not pick up a bug that only experts would recognize, and adding another ten thousand won’t help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statements are statements, and expressions are expressions (in Go)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/statements-are-statements-and-expressions-are-expressions-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 19:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/statements-are-statements-and-expressions-are-expressions-in-go/</guid>
      <description>I got trolled by a facetious article on Go on April 1. But it did trigger a conversation about why Go doesn’t do certain things other languages do.
The answer, in several cases, is that Go chooses to make a clear distinction between expressions and statements. It chooses not to conflate them.
By way of definition, an expression is a thing that has (returns) a value. A statement is an imperative command to do something, but itself does not have a value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory of the firm: opt-in initiatives</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/theory-of-the-firm-optin-initiatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 20:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/theory-of-the-firm-optin-initiatives/</guid>
      <description>I’ve become adamant about making internal initiatives opt-in for the following reason: it brings more information to bear.
For example, at Stack, I started something called “Ask a Nerd”. The goal is to create a channel of communication between our sales people and our developers.
Now, I might easily have pushed for compelling all developers and sales people to participate. It stands to reason: if it’s a good idea, everyone should be part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugs are a failure of prediction</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/bugs-are-a-failure-of-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 23:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/bugs-are-a-failure-of-prediction/</guid>
      <description>We think of bugs as flaws in code. This is incorrect, or at best, banal.
Rather, the essential definition of a bug is that a programmer failed to predict what a piece of code would do.
See, smart programmers wrote the code. Other smart programmers looked at the code. It went into production, and did the wrong thing.
No programmer wanted it to do the wrong thing. They thought it would do the right thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The legacy ad industry is wrong about ad blockers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-legacy-ad-industry-is-wrong-about-ad-blockers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 23:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-legacy-ad-industry-is-wrong-about-ad-blockers/</guid>
      <description>I was recently directed to a couple of papers on browser ad-blocking software (here and here). They are not so much alarmist as they are self-serving and hindered by status quo bias.
Ad blockers remind me of music piracy since the advent of Napster. The technical details are different, but the dynamic is the same — a consumer gets what they want at a lower price, through technical means.
Then, as now, few users thought of themselves as violating any rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding a struct declaration in a text template in Go</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/embedding-a-struct-declaration-in-a-text-template-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 23:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/embedding-a-struct-declaration-in-a-text-template-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a nice little technique I came across in developing gen.
Say you have a text template, and that template is intended to output Go code. You’d like to pass a data structure into the template, and have the structure appear in the template as its own value literal.
There is a printf format string that does just this: %#v
Let’s say you have a template like: p := {{.}}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncanny valley tech recruiting</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/uncanny-valley-tech-recruiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 19:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/uncanny-valley-tech-recruiting/</guid>
      <description>As recruiter pitches show up in my inbox, it’s clear there’s a lot of “fake it til you make it” when it comes to tech terminology.
One arrived today, telling me that “dependency injection” is a hot technology these days, and that their client was hiring people with that skill.
For a short moment, I was impressed that such specificity was included in a cold email — a hint of credibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes, net neutrality is conservative. That’s the problem.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/yes-net-neutrality-is-conservative.-thats-the-problem./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 19:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/yes-net-neutrality-is-conservative.-thats-the-problem./</guid>
      <description>Fred Wilson makes the argument (here and here) that net neutrality is a conservative idea. That’s correct, and that’s the problem.
My definition of “conservative” is “seeking to preserve accreted value”. It fights change, because change is considered dangerous. It is (perhaps rational) risk-aversion and loss-aversion.
For example, environmental protection is conservative. Preferring traditional marriage is conservative.
(You’ll note that people who support those respective ideas are not typically found within the same political tribe, which is my semantic point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My security and privacy tools</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/my-security-and-privacy-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/my-security-and-privacy-tools/</guid>
      <description>A quick list of the things I use to improve my web experience:
HTTPS Everywhere – Does its best to detect whether a site offers HTTPS, and switches to that if so.
DNSCrypt – DNS traffic can be encrypted, too.
Block third-party cookies – In Chrome it’s a checkbox at chrome://settings/content. In Safari, it’s the default. Fluid is a nice Safari wrapper, btw.
AdBlock Plus – Ad blocker that’s open source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A type system in runtime’s clothing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-type-system-in-runtimes-clothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 23:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-type-system-in-runtimes-clothing/</guid>
      <description>Any sufficiently complicated C or Fortran program contains an ad hoc, informally-specified, bug-ridden, slow implementation of half of Common Lisp. — Greenspun
I am reminded of this quote when I see a common pattern in data stores, especially RDBMS. It’s a key-value pattern, along the lines of: Columns: IDType | ID | Value
…combined with application code which branches on the IDType column. The Value (and heck, the identifier) are interpreted differently based on the type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchy and orthogonality in C# and Go</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/hierarchy-and-orthogonality-in-c-sharp-and-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/hierarchy-and-orthogonality-in-c-sharp-and-go/</guid>
      <description>Prompted by this question I got to thinking about methods in C# and Go. It’s another example, I realized, of Go’s (logical) insistence on orthogonality and (stylistic) insistence on flatness/lack of hierarchy.
Go does not allow methods to be defined within a struct (ersatz class) definition. Instead of this, where the method lives in the declaration: type Foo struct { Count, Price int Total() int { // nope return Count * Price } }</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know your guarantees, Go edition</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/know-your-guarantees-go-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 01:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/know-your-guarantees-go-edition/</guid>
      <description>I was directed to a thread about a poor soul who started a project in Go, eventually had to hand it off to the community, and discovered that his original source no longer compiled, due to third-party dependencies having changed. Key quote: Not even the original programmer, with the original files on his original dev machine, can compile the source anymore.
I feel for the guy. Unfortunately, the above quote is not correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The two edges of “culture fit”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-two-edges-of-culture-fit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-two-edges-of-culture-fit/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a smart and funny bit about culture fit. I think it’s brutal and by and large true. [1]
When I first heard the term “culture fit”, I thought intuitively, yes. Great way to build a company. Companies are cultures and we should aim to build them.
Then, not long after, I thought, wait. “Culture fit” among highly-educated-20-something-males-on-the-spectrum might not actually make for a great culture, if it’s going to be of any size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a savvy landlord would handle Airbnb</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/how-a-savvy-landlord-would-handle-airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 03:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/how-a-savvy-landlord-would-handle-airbnb/</guid>
      <description>Megan McArdle describes the understandable discomfort that some tenants and property owners have about Airbnb’ers coming into their buildings.
Airbnb will naturally drive up rents in places where it’s being used. If a tenant has the capacity to pay (e.g.) $2000 for an apartment, but can get an additional (e.g.) $300 a month, the tenant’s capacity to pay is now $2300.
A savvy landlord or condo association would want to capture this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De facto immutability</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/de-facto-immutability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 23:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/de-facto-immutability/</guid>
      <description>Another in a series of posts wherein I spitball about things that computer scientists already know, but have only just occurred to me.
Browsing the new Swift docs reveals that immutability is given pretty high billing. There are two keywords for variable declaration/assignment: let and var.
The former declares an immutable value; the latter a mutable one. The former is used much more often in the examples, providing a hint about the intentions of the designers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Netflix bought from Comcast is a CDN</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-netflix-bought-from-comcast-is-a-cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 00:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-netflix-bought-from-comcast-is-a-cdn/</guid>
      <description>With the hubbub about net neutrality, fast lanes and Netflix, I though I would illustrate what we are dealing with technologically.
Netflix’s deal with Comcast is called “interconnect” or “peering”. It’s part of the wholesale, or B2B, side of the Internet.
Traditionally, Netflix would buy “transit” from a third-party like Cogent. Cogent, in turn, would make a deal with consumer ISPs such as Comcast, Verizon, Time Warner, et al, and thereby deliver Netflix’s bits to consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middle class in NYC</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/middle-class-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 16:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/middle-class-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>There is a notion I hear from time to time that earning (say) $100,000 while living in NYC makes one “middle class”. The logic being, NYC is expensive and $100K doesn’t go as far as it would in other places. Or, that many nearby people earn similar or higher incomes, putting one “in the middle”.
The facts are correct but the logic is exactly backwards. One lives in NYC because one has the means to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC doesn’t need to be Silicon Valley</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/nyc-doesnt-need-to-be-silicon-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 19:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/nyc-doesnt-need-to-be-silicon-valley/</guid>
      <description>[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460804530989694976)
[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460804779560960001)
[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460805162400239617)
[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460806357835579392)
[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460806713596477440)
[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460807092392431616)
[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460807448413372416)
[](https://twitter.com/clipperhouse/status/460807647546331136)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An idea for bookifying the web</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/an-idea-for-bookifying-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 19:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/an-idea-for-bookifying-the-web/</guid>
      <description>I use Pocket, a handy “read it later” tool. The idea is that I can “pocket” a web page by clicking a bookmarklet (or browser extension), and the page is:
 added to a reading list delivered to my device(s) reformatted for readability (the main content is extracted and the page noise is stripped away)  You can see that there are 3 distinct use cases here, which happen to work well together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Components: have we not been here before?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/web-components-have-we-not-been-here-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 16:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/web-components-have-we-not-been-here-before/</guid>
      <description>Addy Osmani describes Web Components, of which an important part is custom tags. The promise: In one word, a future with Web Components is declarative. JavaScript still exists in this future, but is relegated back to a role where it acts as a glue holding the other bits of a component together. Web Apps in the near future will be composed almost entirely from elements (tags). Some of these elements (like the &amp;lt;audio&amp;gt; tag) will be given to you by the browser but others like &amp;lt;slide-show&amp;gt; will be custom elements provided by UI libraries or you can write it yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nesting is state</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/nesting-is-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 18:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/nesting-is-state/</guid>
      <description>There are stylistic debates about how much nesting or indentation one should choose in code. This slide and the one that follows illustrate the issue well. The slide refers to “cognitive load” without explaining, and it occurs to me that nesting is state.
In the first example, if we want to debug around the highlighted line, what do we need to keep in mind? func (g *Gopher) WriteTo(w io.Writer) (size int64, err error) { err = binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Horowitz on wage-fixing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/ben-horowitz-on-wagefixing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 17:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/ben-horowitz-on-wagefixing/</guid>
      <description>I am really, really enjoying Ben Horowitz’s The Hard Thing About Hard Things. It’s blunt and refreshing, and lives up to its title. It’s a nice counter to the notion that running a business is dreamy and life-affirming all the time.
But! I was a bit surprised to find him advocate the sort of behavior that has ensnared a bunch of tech firms in a wage-fixing suit. A good rule of thumb is my Reflexive Principle of Employee Raiding, which states, “If you would be shocked and horrified if Company X hired several of your employees, then you should not hire any of theirs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Stack Overflow and Go have in common</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-stack-overflow-and-go-have-in-common/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 14:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-stack-overflow-and-go-have-in-common/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working at Stack for over three years now, and over the last six months or so I’ve been doing playing with a programming language called Go. Both are highly regarded and, for many, controversial, and I’ve realized what they have in common.
Stack Overflow and Go are both optimized for artifacts. Which is to say, their goal is to create good outcomes that last a long time. Note that this is not the same as optimizing for the pleasure of their users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I optimize conversations</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/how-i-optimize-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 20:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/how-i-optimize-conversations/</guid>
      <description>I had a realization some years ago in working with a person at a previous firm. After many interactions, I noticed that my productivity, my happiness, my motivation consistently were diminished after dealing with them.
I found that I came out of these conversations feeling more burdened than I had going in.
I noticed with certain other people, our conversations were the opposite — I came away with fewer problems, or a new perspective, or food for thought, or feeling freshly challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threshold thinking</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/threshold-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 21:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/threshold-thinking/</guid>
      <description>I consider our industry’s current approach to ads to be wildly inefficient. Very “good” click-through rates are in the single-digit percentages, and more likely one or two orders of magnitude below that.
Let’s assume for the sake of argument that some brand advertising is valuable, which is to say that the impression serves a purpose even if the user doesn’t click.
So, being charitable, 90% of ads that we put on our sites are of no economic value, which is to say, of no value to the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The trouble with interfaces in Go</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-trouble-with-interfaces-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 03:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-trouble-with-interfaces-in-go/</guid>
      <description>I am working on a tool for generics-like functionality in Go. Despite what you may have heard, Go does have generic functionality, in that you can create (e.g.) methods which operate on any type, by using interface{} — the interface that all types implement. For example, you can do something like:
func DoSomething(interface{}) interface{} {
…
}
…where both the input parameter and the output return value are interface{}. It’s quite flexible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New release of gen</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/new-release-of-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 17:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/new-release-of-gen/</guid>
      <description>I’ve a new release of gen, the generics-like tool for Go. It includes API changes so I suggest reading the changelog. Highlights:
Markup instead of command-line Where before you would specify types to gen at the command line, à la gen package.Type, now you simply add tags to types (in comments):
// +gen
type MyType struct {…}
…and the command-line simply becomes gen. This make re-generating easy, the specs are entirely in your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another reason publishers should adopt SSL: referrers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/another-reason-publishers-should-adopt-ssl-referrers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 21:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/another-reason-publishers-should-adopt-ssl-referrers/</guid>
      <description>I previously mentioned that advertising-based publishers should embrace SSL as a product upgrade, a service to their customer. Here’s a more self-interested take.
When a user clicks is on a HTTPS site (such as Google, Hacker News, Twitter*…) and the link to which they navigate is plain HTTP, the referrer header will not be included with the request. So a publisher that receives incoming traffic from such a site will be blind in terms or referrers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishers and SSL</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/publishers-and-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 19:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/publishers-and-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a good article about why news sites on the web are slow to embrace SSL. The short answer is, the advertising services they use are not prepared to support it.
This seems like an opportunity for publishers. How about this: make SSL available now, and turn off ads until the technical issues are settled. That’s right.
Firstly, it sends a pro-consumer message: “we’ve upgraded our site at no charge to you”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-credentialing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/multicredentialing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 01:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/multicredentialing/</guid>
      <description>John Maeda of RISD has a riff about the future of college credentials, including the notion of an automated ‘degree’, which is generated by a machine based on the sum your achievements. He makes an analogy to Coinstar: pour in a bunch of individually valuable stuff, get out some paper which aggregates its value.
It’s not that crazy of an idea; it only sounds crazy because we are using our current terminology of credentials as a certificate of education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress bars cannot be accurate</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/progress-bars-cannot-be-accurate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 01:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/progress-bars-cannot-be-accurate/</guid>
      <description>We all see progress bars and some of us even implement them. And we’ve all seen how hilariously wrong they can be. There’s a reason for that.
In order for a progress bar to be accurate, a program needs to determine how long it will take to run, prior to running it. It needs to know how much work it will do before doing it.
It seems to me that the only way to accurately know how much work a program has to do, is to do the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your site doesn’t need a novel progress indicator</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/your-site-doesnt-need-a-novel-progress-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 14:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/your-site-doesnt-need-a-novel-progress-indicator/</guid>
      <description>There’s been healthy talk about progress indicators in the age of ajax. In our will-to-design I think some things are being missed.
First, your browser’s UI already includes a progress indicator, and perhaps more than one:
Your user is accustomed to these things, not unlike the back button. Why would we introduce a novel UI element, adding to the user’s cognitive load, when we already have them?
The shortcoming here is that, perhaps, the browser doesn’t offer obvious programmatic access to the above, or that it doesn’t occur to us to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language and social signaling</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/language-and-social-signaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 19:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/language-and-social-signaling/</guid>
      <description>I like language. I came to it causally at first, and more formally of late.
I’ve always been amused by out-of-fashion terminology (I say “good lord” a lot) and like the feeling of choosing words a bit differently than others might.
Expressing things wrongly, or inserting ignorant-sounding bits, is fun. I regularly say “the rock and roll” or “the YouTube” because it’s funny and evokes an old-timey ignorance. (It also expresses a bit of humility: comparing what I know to what is knowable about music and the Internet, I am an old-timey ignoramus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.6% of what?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/1.6-percent-of-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 21:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/1.6-percent-of-what/</guid>
      <description>The NSA has published a paper claiming that it “touches” only 1.6% of Internet traffic. Now, 1.6% of something the size of the Internet is already enormous, but let’s demonstrate that the number represents are much larger share of human communications than one might intuit.
First, let’s assume that the NSA is interested only in “novel” traffic — human-created, unique data that depicts an individual’s activities or intentions.
My assumption is that the NSA is not interested in inspecting the actual bits that comprise Arrested Development or a cat video; it’s precisely the same data being transferred over and over, month after month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incidence of compulsion</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/incidence-of-compulsion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 00:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/incidence-of-compulsion/</guid>
      <description>This is an encouraging story about Google exploring the ability to encrypt ‘sitting files’ in their Google Drive product. This is distinct from something like SSL, which only protects items in transit; most companies store the canonical file in the clear.
Declan mentions problem #1, which is that encrypted files are hard to search, and search is Google’s thing. Take that away, and the product is devalued.
What is less thoroughly explored is that, for the government to actually be impeded in retrieving your files, Google would have to be legitimately ignorant of your key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epistemology and human factors: deal with ‘em</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/epistemology-and-human-factors-deal-with-em/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 22:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/epistemology-and-human-factors-deal-with-em/</guid>
      <description>This study that Google conducted to find predictors for success in their hiring process is very interesting. Among the things that are not predictive of success: the candidate’s GPA, their ability to solve brain-teasers, and which manager did the interview.
The hiring process is very difficult. It’s largely intuitive and we make decisions based on personal heuristics. All of which is okay — in fact, we don’t have much of a choice, since actual predictors are hard to come by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCD is id, high standards are ego</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/ocd-is-id-high-standards-are-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 18:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/ocd-is-id-high-standards-are-ego/</guid>
      <description>As programmers, we have a powerful tool that we deploy often: OCD.
While the name connotes a ‘disorder’, certain obsessive behaviors make for very effective programmers. Remember, code that is 99% right is wrong. Crashingly, money-losingly wrong. OCD is made for this profession.
Its strength, however, is also its weakness: it monopolizes our attention. Our ability to dive deep, to focus, to simply not let things go, makes for amazing code and terrible time management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few thoughts on flat</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-flat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 19:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-flat/</guid>
      <description>I played with iOS7 today for a bit and discussed the flat design with a couple of Stack’ers. I also read Matt Gemmell’s review, and John Gruber’s take on flatness.
The unifying sentiment seems to be: in the early days of smartphones (say 2007), buttons needed to look like buttons so we know where to click. Since then, we’ve all become familiar with the idea of tapping icons, so perhaps we don’t need to make the affordances quite so obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For want of parens in Ruby</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/for-want-of-parens-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 01:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/for-want-of-parens-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Ruby is beautiful in many ways. The opportunities to create tight, readable code are impressive. More than other languages, it affords the opportunity to make code look like what it does.
One syntactic wart, however, is functions. I’ll make an analogy with JavaScript, where myFunction()
executes myFunction, while myFunction
is a variable that refers to the function, that can be passed as, say, a callback. In Ruby, parentheses around method arguments are optional, such that my_thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fasctimidating</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/fasctimidating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 17:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/fasctimidating/</guid>
      <description>Chris Baus laments that developers are rarely impressed by other developers. It’s often true. But why are developers hard to (outwardly) impress?
For many of us, we base our identity on being special in a particular way: that we can see meaning in things that others find to be gibberish, like, say, computer code or big piles of raw data.
It is a direct tweak to our pleasure center when we have insights that others don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alerts as spam</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/alerts-as-spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 15:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/alerts-as-spam/</guid>
      <description>I went to a talk last night by John Allspaw at Etsy, about alerts and how they are hard to get right.
The short story is, signal-to-noise. Most alerting systems don’t alert, because they are largely false-positive. Due to sheer volume, the recipients of those alerts start inventing their own subjective algorithm as to what deserves attention.
Those human factors are the hard part. Alerts require serious design, and need to be designed with the knowledge that they will be consumed in the context of several other alerting systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if ‘source code’ were a serialized syntax tree?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-if-source-code-were-a-serialized-syntax-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 02:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-if-source-code-were-a-serialized-syntax-tree/</guid>
      <description>At the risk of revealing my lack of a CompSci degree: what if ‘source code’ were replaced by serialized syntax trees?
What if the canonical ‘source’ of an application were not source code, as created by humans, but rather a serialized format of the syntax tree?
The workflow would go like this. You check out the repository. You make changes, and debug, to your satisfaction. Your local changes are still ‘source code’ as we currently understand it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging is debugging</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/debugging-is-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 17:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/debugging-is-debugging/</guid>
      <description>I use CoffeeScript here and there. And JavaScript everywhere else.
Depending on the scenario, and this is a matter of taste, CoffeeScript is more elegant, readable, and usable.
When offering this notion, inevitably there is a complaint about “debugging.” CS is generating code, it’s a layer of abstraction, which will lead to frustration, etc.
The question is, compared to what? When JavaScript is not behaving as you wish, what do you do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your phone is faster than Amtrak’s wifi</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/your-phone-is-faster-than-amtraks-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 15:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/your-phone-is-faster-than-amtraks-wifi/</guid>
      <description>Amtrak is improving its wifi, it claims. Fine. The problem is, it’ll never be faster than your phone’s 4G connection.
Why? Because Amtrak’s wifi uses the same 4G network. So take your 4G, send the bits through an additional router, contend with your neighbors’ bits, and you’ve got Amtrak wifi. (This is true of the wifi on the bus too, it’s not about Amtrak specifically.)
Now, in theory, there are some decent reasons to use their wifi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad blocking, like piracy, is a market phenomenon</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/ad-blocking-like-piracy-is-a-market-phenomenon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/ad-blocking-like-piracy-is-a-market-phenomenon/</guid>
      <description>A French ISP has started blocking ads at the router level for its customers, enabled by default. Advertisers are, not surprisingly, upset.
What Free.fr is doing will probably not turn out to be legal. It’s clearly meant as a poke in the eye to content-driven advertisers like Google. It ensures a re-arguing of net neutrality.
What I haven’t heard is any objection by users. The move is, politics aside, a differentiator for the ISP’s service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor costs make way for Maslow</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/labor-costs-make-way-for-maslow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 02:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/labor-costs-make-way-for-maslow/</guid>
      <description>That Apple, and other companies, are deciding to move manufacturing back to the United States is evidence of the diminishing importance of labor costs in decision-making. This implies several things.
Labor is around 4–5% of the retail cost for a computer, according to the article, and will continue to fall as automation increases. Labor costs are a bottom-line decision: a way to extract profit from a sale that has already happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A political approach to hiring creatives</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-political-approach-to-hiring-creatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 18:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-political-approach-to-hiring-creatives/</guid>
      <description>This article offers a lot of sound advice on hiring a designer. As techies, we’re often out of our depth in knowing what a good designer is — often, we hire a decorator instead (or as the article calls it, a stylist).
Style is important, but it’s not the main goal of design. Design encompasses the user’s whole experience. Design is the product.
The designer is the user’s advocate. I mean that in the full political sense: they are a public defender making the case for a client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s political privacy game</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/microsofts-political-privacy-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 18:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/microsofts-political-privacy-game/</guid>
      <description>I’ve suggested many times that Microsoft should disable third-party cookies by default in IE10 (and Safari does currently). This would be strategic for them: it devalues Google’s main income source and allows Microsoft to trumpet a commitment to privacy.
This cookie-based approach would functionally prevent user information from going to third parties. (Microsoft has not made any commitment to setting this default.)
Microsoft has, however, chosen a more political path to the same goal, by sending a “Do Not Track” header in IE10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quaintness of “content” vs “infrastructure”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-quaintness-of-content-vs-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 03:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-quaintness-of-content-vs-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a really informative article on the economics of Google’s fiber offer. One of the key takeaways is that Google’s ownership of high-bandwidth content (YouTube) gives them leverage in peering arrangements.
This is a lovely turnabout, in my opinion. It allows Google to hang carrots/wield sticks that most others can’t. Fighting incumbents ain’t beanbag.
There was a time when arguments about the net (neutrality in particular) hinged on a Luddish mental model that “content” and “infrastructure” were, and should be, different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good might be the enemy of the perfect with software patents</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-good-might-be-the-enemy-of-the-perfect-with-software-patents/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 02:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-good-might-be-the-enemy-of-the-perfect-with-software-patents/</guid>
      <description>I have a few concerns, relating to unintended consequences, with a proposed loser-pays bill on software patents.
I quite like the idea of loser-pays, and it is the standard in many parts of the world. And I certainly don’t like the current state of affairs with software patents. But the intended narrowness of the bill may make things worse.
Firstly, it attempts to define a software patent as anything that might be implemented on a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two, billion-dollar UI mistakes in Windows 8</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/two-billiondollar-ui-mistakes-in-windows-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 18:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/two-billiondollar-ui-mistakes-in-windows-8/</guid>
      <description>I am very interested in Windows 8 both as a user and as a tech industry watcher. Big bet, big changes.
Given the size of the bet, I believe Microsoft is making two UI mistakes that will cost them billions if they are released.
It took me, a developer and lifelong Windows user, quite a while to figure out how to search from the start screen. There is no search box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolution vs “real estate”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/resolution-vs-real-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 03:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/resolution-vs-real-estate/</guid>
      <description>The new Retina Macbook looks quite beautiful, but from a productivity standpoint I am a bit disappointed. While they have quadrupled the pixel count (to 2880 x 1800), they have not increased real estate, per se.
In other words, the number of windows or characters or columns displayable on the screen has not changed — it is essentially a 1440 x 900 pixel display with increased sharpness. It’s like a new printer with a higher dpi, but the same paper size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluency</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/fluency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 18:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/fluency/</guid>
      <description>At my ripe old age one might expect me to give up programming and focus more on management. Which I do, if informally. But I have never seen the need to put aside programming in order to manage.
Good programmers inevitably end up promoted into a management role. It’s a hard role: the demands on one’s time, and the sources of one’s satisfaction, change dramatically.
Too often, this means that one no longer writes production code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This way madness lies (thankfully)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/this-way-madness-lies-thankfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/this-way-madness-lies-thankfully/</guid>
      <description>Tim Lee offers two views of the economic case for innovation. I am certainly more Hayekian — I think expertise and information is inherently dispersed and the Hayekian view is more granular, if you will. It’s more likely to discover and serve niches and inefficiencies.
I think Tim hits the nail on the head that: Building an iPad didn’t just require millions of dollars, it required that those millions be spent by the right company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservative and liberal</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/conservative-and-liberal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 22:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/conservative-and-liberal/</guid>
      <description>The ideas of conservative and liberal have become very confused, and in many cases exactly backwards. Let’s try to understand them — as adjectives instead of nouns — and strip them of some connotations.
A conservative idea is one that sees value in limiting change. The assumption is that an organic system is a long accretion of wisdom or value, and should not be changed lightly. The built-up information in the system might not be obvious, and so changing it risks a greater loss than one anticipates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s next for Better Bird?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/whats-next-for-better-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 16:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/whats-next-for-better-bird/</guid>
      <description>We’ve got a few hundred folks using Better Bird, my Chrome extension for fixing the Twitter web UI, and I’m thrilled.
I need feedback on what to do next. What do you think?
[polldaddy poll=6051316]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inorganic app</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-inorganic-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 02:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-inorganic-app/</guid>
      <description>It occurs to me, as I look at my Google+ stream for the first time in two months, the reason I never use it: it never had a chance to grow on me.
It’s beautifully implemented. It fills in niches that other platforms miss. It’s not an imitation of Facebook or Twitter (though it is obviously a reaction to those things).
No, the problem is that it is inorganic. It revealed itself to the world fully formed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A failure of empathy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-failure-of-empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-failure-of-empathy/</guid>
      <description>Consider for a moment the logic of the leading paragraph of this article: Research suggests that consumers spend only about one second looking at nutrition information when making myriad choices. A parent dashing through the grocery store aisles with kids in tow has to decide, in that one second, which is better: Triscuit vs. Saltines vs. Wheat Thins vs. Ritz? This is why Americans need a simple, standardized and truthful label on the front of all packaged foods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C# should be truthy-y</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/c-sharp-should-be-truthyy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 05:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/c-sharp-should-be-truthyy/</guid>
      <description>While “truthy” values in JavaScript can cause no small amount of heartache, one must admit they help readability. For objects anyway, it’s very nice to say if (object) {…} and get on with business. If the object is null or undefined, “false” strikes me as a perfectly legitimate behavior in that context.
I’d love to see something similar in C# — not truthiness, but an implicit test for existence.
Every object in C# has a ToString method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody cares about “channels”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/nobody-cares-about-channels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 06:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/nobody-cares-about-channels/</guid>
      <description>There are rumors afoot that Apple will offer TV channels as apps in an upcoming release. This might work as an interim idea, but it has no legs long-term.
This idea is not new — for years, people have been arguing for “a la carte” cable television. The idea being, instead of simply signing up for several dozen channels, a consumer might instead select their own menu of individual channels, and pay accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suspension of disbelief</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/suspension-of-disbelief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 16:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/suspension-of-disbelief/</guid>
      <description>You watch a movie. In order to get something from it, you have to enter the world that it presents. You must suspend disbelief.
This is essential for the product to work correctly. If you are unwilling to believe, say, that space mercenaries have Wookiee friends, or that the bumbling Bluth family exists — then it’s very unlikely the product is for you.
Restated, you know full well that none of what you perceive actually exists, but you believe it in order to get something out of the experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try “Better Bird”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/try-better-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 18:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/try-better-bird/</guid>
      <description>I created a Chrome extension to fix what I think are some rough edges and poor choices in the Twitter web app. Have a look:
Some things it does:
 Moves the content to the left side, where it should be. Resolves t.co, bit.ly and other shortened links, so you know where you are clicking. Widens the content and optionally uses a nicer font. Exposes your Saved Searches, which are otherwise obscured, and notifies you of new matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craigslist can help fix the NYC apartment market</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/craigslist-can-help-fix-the-nyc-apartment-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 17:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/craigslist-can-help-fix-the-nyc-apartment-market/</guid>
      <description>As I’ve written in the past, there are several unique inefficiencies to the Manhattan apartment market. Many can’t be helped in the short term, owing to an endemically tight market.
One that can be helped is information asymmetry. Brokers consider the simple knowledge of an available apartment to be proprietary information. That’s absurd, and serves no one’s interests except the middleman.
Obviously, prospective renters would like to know more about an apartment before pursuing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Owning a data type, or, be the switchboard</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/owning-a-data-type-or-be-the-switchboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 19:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/owning-a-data-type-or-be-the-switchboard/</guid>
      <description>I was chatting with my colleagues at Stack Exchange the other day and we wondered what it means to “own” a data type.
The best recent example is Twitter. They effectively “own” the format of short, one-to-many messaging. Their “product”, the web app, is good but not that compelling on its own. The fact that everyone who wants to participate in their particular communication protocol needs to pass through their “switchboard” — well, that is compelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disrupting the NYC rental information market</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/disrupting-the-nyc-rental-information-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 15:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/disrupting-the-nyc-rental-information-market/</guid>
      <description>The Manhattan apartment rental market is unique, as anyone who has experienced it will tell you. The very low vacancy rate (high demand) allows for behavior that other markets don’t bear.
The first is the idea of a broker for trivial transactions. Many (most?) apartment buildings require that you go through a broker, paying a fee between 1–2 months’ rent.
This is not a “broker” in the sense of someone who saves you time by shopping on your behalf (though some do that).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What legacy politicians actually fear</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-legacy-politicians-actually-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 21:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-legacy-politicians-actually-fear/</guid>
      <description>I was at the PIPA/SOPA protest in front of the offices of Senators Schumer and Gillibrand today. All fine and good, but why should the senators care?
The immediate answer is, they won’t…but bear with me.
These senators, like others, succeed because they are able to monetize their influence. This means that they expect would-be influencers — like, say, the entertainment or technology or finance industries — to put their money where their mouths are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The friction constituency</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-friction-constituency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 03:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-friction-constituency/</guid>
      <description>Having learned that both the Chamber of Commerce and the AFL-CIO support SOPA, it’s becoming clearer to me just how much of our economy is based on extracting rents from friction.
Both big business and big labor depend on it. Freer markets drive down the cost of goods as new entrants undercut incumbents. A freer market is very threatening to existing businesses, and I wouldn’t want it any other way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality of life in NYC</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/quality-of-life-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/quality-of-life-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>Every time I get out of NYC, I am reminded at what we put up with to live here. It’s a known trope: we deal with sh*t that suburbanites couldn’t imagine, in exchange for being around amazing people (and companies, and $$).
There are three basic elements to living, and it is in these areas that NYC residents fare worse than middle-class suburbs. Fix these fundamentals, and quality of life ramps up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please don’t lobby</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/please-dont-lobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 15:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/please-dont-lobby/</guid>
      <description>I agree with Clay Johnson that the our industry’s ignorance of Congress might be greater than Congress’ ignorance of the Internet. He comes to the conclusion that we need to lobby more.
I disagree. Throwing money down the lobby hole starts a vicious circle. We pay to play, and Congress finds new ways to milk the cow — or to create problems that justify their existence. As Clay Shirky put it: Institutions will try to preserve the problem to which they are the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me doing techno</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/me-doing-techno/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 15:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/me-doing-techno/</guid>
      <description>Watch the original first. Then:
[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1dvltmlBVNU]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can’t mobile apps have URLs?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/why-cant-mobile-apps-have-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 03:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/why-cant-mobile-apps-have-urls/</guid>
      <description>Dave Winer laments that mobile apps are not universally addressable via a locator like a URL.
Actually, they are, it’s just underexploited. For example, this little radio app allows me to deep-link specific radio stations as tiles on my (Win Phone 7) home screen.
Guess what? The tile has a URL, pointed to a specific place in the app. Now, I haven’t dug deeply enough to know about the security boundaries, but it seems to me it would be a small step to allow the app to register a namespace on the phone (app://appid) and expose endpoints to any other app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack for viewing WSJ stories</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/hack-for-viewing-wsj-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 15:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/hack-for-viewing-wsj-stories/</guid>
      <description>The Wall Street Journal restricts access to some stories — as when it will show you the first paragraph or two as a “Subscribe Content Preview”.
There’s an easy way to get around this if you want the whole story. (I am using the Chrome browser for this, should be similar in others.)
 Select the story headline, and right click to “Search Google for…”   Hopefully the desired story will be at the top of the search results, under News…   Click it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The binary web</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-binary-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 21:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-binary-web/</guid>
      <description>It’s easy to see the web as sets of advances that come in waves. The first was its emergence as a consumer (and corporate) phenomenon, starting with Netscape and continuing through Internet Explorer 6 (which, we often forget, was the first “legitimate” browser for many businesses).
The second wave was Ajax and broadband. This combination allowed web sites to act less like pages and more like applications — responsive enough for things like email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The law is not Turing complete</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-law-is-not-turing-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 20:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-law-is-not-turing-complete/</guid>
      <description>In recent comments on Hacker News, I suggested, with some snark, that the definition of net neutrality is slippery and ad-hoc, and therefore exploitable. I was promptly voted down.
In this case, an ISP in Canada has introduced data caps — a reasonable if undesirable thing — and then went on to make their own video service exempt from counting against these caps.
Shady? Sure. Does it violate the suggested definitions of neutrality?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going about your business, or pleasure</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/going-about-your-business-or-pleasure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 23:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/going-about-your-business-or-pleasure/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t tried Google+ (pronounced ploo, the French way), but I note that there hasn’t been the dismissive pile-on that greeted Buzz and Wave. My meta-analysis is that they might be on to something.
It’s been noted many times that Google has a social graph, even if they haven’t presented it as such. They know who your friends are via Gmail, and they know what you are interested in via Search and its many tentacles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NYT paywall is about segmenting, not security</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-nyt-paywall-is-about-segmenting-not-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 23:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-nyt-paywall-is-about-segmenting-not-security/</guid>
      <description>It may be intemperate of me, but why do geeks respond in such a…Pavlovian way when given the opportunity to assume another person’s stupidity? The latest exhibit is Gizmodo, claiming that the New York Times has implemented their paywall poorly.
The paywall’s prima-facie purpose is to limit your ability to read articles past 20 a month, in the hope of converting you to a paid subscriber.
In truth, the NYT has very little ability to tell who you are, and therefore to count how many articles you’ve read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inversion of scarcity</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/inversion-of-scarcity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 20:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/inversion-of-scarcity/</guid>
      <description>Every business, if it’s smart, should realize that the Internet has the ability to drop out its pricing floor, or more precisely, to eliminate the scarcity on which price depends. This is what is usually meant by the catchphrase “disruption.”
What often happens, subtly, is that the locus of scarcity is reversed — in the consumer’s favor.
Consider information businesses, like newspapers, classified ads, Bloomberg, and even employment agencies. It used to be that the information they supplied was scarce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implicit vs. explicit social graphs</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/implicit-vs.-explicit-social-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 20:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/implicit-vs.-explicit-social-graphs/</guid>
      <description>There are two kinds of social graphs in the world, explicit and implicit. The explicit ones are the most rare and give their owners disproportionate market values.
The two I am thinking of are Facebook (private market value around $40B) and LinkedIn, with a public market cap of ~$6B. What makes their graphs explicit is that two individuals deliberately and mutually describe their connection with one another.
Implicit “soft” graphs include Twitter and Google (via Gmail).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design is information</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/design-is-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 06:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/design-is-information/</guid>
      <description>It seems to me the companies with the greatest customer loyalty are those where design has a strong presence in the corporate culture. I don’t mean this in a touchy-feely way. I mean that customer loyalty is worth billions of dollars, and most companies see fit to leave that on the table.
Design is product. Fonts and colors are not design — they are decoration. Design is the hard work of understanding everything a customer might do, or want to do, how they will do it, and how they will be rewarded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every programming problem…</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/every-programming-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 20:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/every-programming-problem/</guid>
      <description>…can be entirely described in these four dimensions:
 Cache: The browser is a cache for a web page, whose canonical version lives on a server. A web page is a cache for structured data, whose canonical version lives in (say) SQL. Structured data is a cache for bits that live on a spinning piece of rust. The questions for the programmer are, how similar is a piece of data to its canonical source, and how similar does it have to be?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the jQuery “jump” on slide</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/fixing-the-jquery-jump-on-slide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/fixing-the-jquery-jump-on-slide/</guid>
      <description>You may notice in some situations, when using jQuery’s slideDown(), that the last little bit of the animation “jumps”. It feel un-smooth and frustrates those who like to dot our i’s. (Here an explanation.)
The main issue is that the browser (and thus jQuery) is uncertain about the height of the element that is sliding. This, in turn, is based on uncertainty about the _width_ — the width determines how lines wrap, and dictates the height.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Microsoft can make Visual Studio cool among the cool kids</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/how-microsoft-can-make-visual-studio-cool-among-the-cool-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/how-microsoft-can-make-visual-studio-cool-among-the-cool-kids/</guid>
      <description>I am quite partial to ASP.net MVC and C#. I’ve played with other platforms, esp Ruby, which have appeal as well.
While many aspects of the platform are, imho, technologically ahead of its competition (LINQ, Intellisense and Razor), I can’t shake the feeling that MS still appeals primarily to those with an enterprise background. Which is to say, the cool kids are choosing Rails and doing their editing on a Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome breaks 10% market share; modern browsers at 80%</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/chrome-breaks-10-percent-market-share-modern-browsers-at-80-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 11:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/chrome-breaks-10-percent-market-share-modern-browsers-at-80-percent/</guid>
      <description>The headline say most of it. Google’s Chrome browser popped up over 10% market share for January. Modern browsers* are creeping up to around 80% market share, which means the user experience of the web is moving forward.
Something I hadn’t noticed previous: Internet Explorer 7 has substantially less market share than its predecessor, IE 6. So, when a site decides not to support IE 6, their justification for supporting IE 7 is even less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is what a non-neutral net looks like</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/this-is-what-a-nonneutral-net-looks-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 07:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/this-is-what-a-nonneutral-net-looks-like/</guid>
      <description>Gogo, which offers in-flight Wi-fi on a bunch of airlines, is now offering Facebook at no charge — but access to other sites will cost $$.
This violates net neutrality, no? Obviously, certain content is getting special treatment by an ISP, while other content is being blocked unless you pay up.
Am I being facetious? Not really. Discriminatory pricing is generally pro-consumer when you look into it. Different prices for different products usually translates to discounts, not price increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A call for industry-wide pixel-doubling</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-call-for-industrywide-pixeldoubling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 16:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-call-for-industrywide-pixeldoubling/</guid>
      <description>Computer screens have not changed much over the last 20 years, relative to other technologies like processing power and bandwidth. Yes, panels are better in many ways in terms of color accuracy and “resolution”. But most applications are designed around an assumption of 72 or 96 pixels per inch.
I put “resolution” in quotes because, while screens have inched up in absolute pixels-per-inch, we are not using those pixels effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet is not a public commons, and it is not Beetlejuice</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-internet-is-not-a-public-commons-and-it-is-not-beetlejuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 10:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-internet-is-not-a-public-commons-and-it-is-not-beetlejuice/</guid>
      <description>There are some stories making the rounds that “the Internet” is a public commons built on private property. This is wrong.
Firstly, is nothing public about it. “The Internet”, as we know is, exists and is useful because it is private. Or, more precisely, it is a lot of private entities working together because they choose to.
Those private entities include the corporations that provide the infrastructure and services (ISP’s like Comcast and services like Google).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The scourge of paid prioritization</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-scourge-of-paid-prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 07:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-scourge-of-paid-prioritization/</guid>
      <description>I received a pair of earmuffs today via Amazon Prime. Great service! They got to New York in just two days, all the way from a Nevada warehouse.
I feel bad, though. Clearly, by my paying extra for this service, I’ve moved others into Amazon’s slow lane. For that, I apologize.
I downloaded a new Justin Bieber Gnarls Barkley track on iTunes just now. It took seconds! Being curious sort, I discovered that Apple is paying a company called Akamai to store the file nearby so I can get it quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Ricky Gervais doesn’t understand about God</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-ricky-gervais-doesnt-understand-about-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-ricky-gervais-doesnt-understand-about-god/</guid>
      <description>I am not a religious person. I also happen to believe that religious people bear the brunt of more everyday bigotry than most groups.
I have heard maybe two or three clearly racists sentiments in my life. By which I mean, uttered in my presence. I hear a similar number of slights against religious people every week, probably.
So upon reading Ricky Gervais’ explanation of his atheism, I had to cringe at his understanding of religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Bernanke’s list of economic participants</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/ben-bernankes-list-of-economic-participants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/ben-bernankes-list-of-economic-participants/</guid>
      <description>Bernanke: “The Federal Reserve cannot solve all the economy’s problems on its own. That will take time and the combined efforts of many parties, including the central bank, Congress, the administration, regulators and the private sector.”
Note the order in which he ranks participants in the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Fred Wilson arguing for “Content Neutrality”?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/is-fred-wilson-arguing-for-content-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/is-fred-wilson-arguing-for-content-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>Fred Wilson, whom I admire, comments on a recent dust-up where a content provider blocked their programming from customers of a specific ISP. This is the kind of stuff that should not happen on the web. […]I see more signs every day that we need some basic rules governing Internet access. Maybe we shouldn’t call it Net Neutrality. Maybe we should call it a bill of rights for consumers on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A couple of easy wins with SQL indexes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-couple-of-easy-wins-with-sql-indexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-couple-of-easy-wins-with-sql-indexes/</guid>
      <description>I was lucky enough to watch a great talk by SQL expert Brent Ozar courtesy of Fog Creek. A couple of actionable takeaways that stuck with me are about creating and choosing indexes.
Indexes in SQL for me are kind of a black art. You look at Query Execution plans, try to intuit where the work is being done, and then make a guess as to what index might help. Then you see if things are “faster”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market share for the taking, or, outrunning the bear</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/market-share-for-the-taking-or-outrunning-the-bear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/market-share-for-the-taking-or-outrunning-the-bear/</guid>
      <description>Much of the commentary I’ve seen for today’s announcement of Windows Phone 7 revolves around whether Microsoft can catch up with Apple’s iPhone and Google’s Android. Fair enough; feature-wise, they are in the same ballpark.
But Microsoft need not triumph over the “big two” in terms of mindshare. In fact, Apple and Google aren’t the big two at all. Who is? Nokia and RIM.
Between them, their operating systems command around 60% of the mobile market — but this number falling rapidly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding “magic strings” in jQuery, C# and ASP.net MVC</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/avoiding-magic-strings-in-jquery-c-sharp-and-asp.net-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 16:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/avoiding-magic-strings-in-jquery-c-sharp-and-asp.net-mvc/</guid>
      <description>The longer I program, the less tolerance I have for “magic strings”. You might be familiar with them — they are strings that have programmatic meaning but are trapped between quotes in another language.
A classic example is SQL held in a string variable within your C#/PHP/whatever code. It might just as easily be HTML in your Javascript.
The problem is that this code is meaningless outside of its domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alikewise learnings #1: DIY PR</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/alikewise-learnings-sharp1-diy-pr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 21:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/alikewise-learnings-sharp1-diy-pr/</guid>
      <description>Thought I would write a few posts to reflect on what I’ve learned with my startup, Alikewise, day jobs, and NYC. This is the first.
Quick history: I decided to leave a comfortable job at a great design firm in early 2009 to pursue this idea, spent about a year getting things off the ground, and launched earlier this year. A couple of months ago I took an opportunity at Stack Overflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sherman’s law of prior knowledge, or, predicting the past</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/shermans-law-of-prior-knowledge-or-predicting-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/shermans-law-of-prior-knowledge-or-predicting-the-past/</guid>
      <description>“When a disaster happens, large or small, there is a 100% chance that a headline will be written claiming ignored warnings.” I’ve come to realize, that’s the narrative. It’s always the narrative, and the details of the incident matter little.
Apple Engineer Told Jobs IPhone Antenna Might Cut Calls
BP warned of rig fault ten years ago
Bush Warned of Hijackings Before 9&amp;frasl;11
…etc. It’s not that any of these folks are blameless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The busiest people at Apple right now…</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-busiest-people-at-apple-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-busiest-people-at-apple-right-now/</guid>
      <description>…are the ones planning the hardware recall. The second busiest are the ones figuring out how to coat the antenna with an electrical insulator that doesn’t hurt the aesthetics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When “infographics” jump the shark</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/when-infographics-jump-the-shark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 09:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/when-infographics-jump-the-shark/</guid>
      <description>Mashable offers an “infographic” describing Google’s history in social networking. And it’s pretty and all well and good, except that the graphic adds no information.
Rather, it’s simply a set of data points that happen to have been put into an image. It’s as if Illustrator had an “Import from Excel” function.
Infographics are supposed to add information, by giving you a visual or intuitive sense of, say, proportion or relationships or trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS is the least of your problems</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/https-is-the-least-of-your-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 07:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/https-is-the-least-of-your-problems/</guid>
      <description>It’s cool that the EFF is offering a Firefox extension to use SSL where it’s available. I prefer to encrypt things too, but really, that’s the least of your problems.
As I am sure you know, HTTPS simply encrypts data between your computer and the web server, while it’s in transit. It does nothing to ensure that your data is handled correctly at the other end.
When you hear about credit card or other privacy breaches, it’s usually due to mishandling — databases that get into the wrong hands, or software flaws that reveal information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacking up</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/stacking-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 17:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/stacking-up/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce that I’ve taken a job over at Stack Overflow.
I’ve been a reader and admirer of Joel and Jeff for some years now, so I am thrilled to be working alongside them. (Hopefully they won’t catch on to the fact that I don’t write code, I merely copy-and-paste from Stack Overflow.)
In fact, I wasn’t really looking for a job, what with Alikewise and some freelance gigs I’ve been doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware the truth-tellers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/beware-the-truthtellers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2010 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/beware-the-truthtellers/</guid>
      <description>I find it is so funny and ironic when a person has to tell you they are telling the truth before they tell you the true thing that is truthful. Today, as part of a otherwise interesting and opinionated post, we learn: I try to be a totally dispassionate truth teller.
Um, who doesn’t? I assume that when any person writes something, they believe themselves to be telling the truth, or offering an honest opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please don’t write “efficient” CSS</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/please-dont-write-efficient-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2010 06:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/please-dont-write-efficient-css/</guid>
      <description>Contra many smart people, I am going to make a contrarian request: please do not attempt to optimize your CSS for performance. Instead, please optimize for correctness, specificity and maintainability.
A quick bit of philosophical background. CSS is a declarative language, not unlike HTML and (basic) SQL. It is designed to describe what you want, but not how to execute it. Thus, declarative languages have no verbs — only nouns and adjectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>0.facebook.com is not neutral</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/0.facebook.com-is-not-neutral/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 17:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/0.facebook.com-is-not-neutral/</guid>
      <description>A while back I mentioned the idea that some content sites would offer free shipping for their bits. It would be the inevitable result of metered pricing on the Internet, an idea with which major (wired) carriers are experimenting.
For example, ESPN might make a deal with Comcast to say “any video from ESPN flowing over Comcast’s network will not count against the customer’s bandwidth bill.” Basically, ESPN becomes toll-free for the customer, not unlike an 800 number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe: call it Flash 11 already</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/adobe-call-it-flash-11-already/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 19:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/adobe-call-it-flash-11-already/</guid>
      <description>I feel like I’ve been hearing about Flash 10.1 forever. The earliest public announcement I can find is October 5 of last year. That’s over 6 months of development for a point release.
Which is entirely understandable — it’s a “maintenance” release, in the sense that most of the goodness is under the covers. Hardware acceleration, better mobile, more platforms. Sounds like it will fix a lot of performance and reliability problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standards: why?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/standards-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 17:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/standards-why/</guid>
      <description>There has been some fun stuff today following Steve Jobs missive on Flash and standards. Joe Hewitt (former Facebook and Mozilla dev and rock star): How it should go: browsers innovate differently, users pick the best one, later W3C standardizes what users chose, losing browsers conform.
Sachin: Browsers aren’t innovating. They are just trying to comply with standards and fix bugs and performance
 Right now browser updates fix bugs and add application features, but can’t enhance the functionality of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: random sort order in C#</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/tip-random-sort-order-in-c-sharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 09:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/tip-random-sort-order-in-c-sharp/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to randomize the display of a List on my site — meaning I would retrieve (say) 20 records, but display only 5, chosen at random. I was imagining a loop that generates a bunch of random indexes, which I use to individually pull elements from the list. Yuck.
The solution I found is much more elegant — two lines! To randomize your list, simply: var rnd = new Random();</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epistemology in everyday life</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/epistemology-in-everyday-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 09:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/epistemology-in-everyday-life/</guid>
      <description>In school, (cough) years ago, I did a bit of epistemology. It’s the study of knowledge. It asks the questions “why do we know that?” and “how will we find that out?”.
It’s infused through everything we do, we just might not realize it. A couple of practical examples.
Markets
One big difference between left and right is trust in markets. The left will say “here is what we need, now how do we get markets (people) to go there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear tech journalists: please announce a one-year, self-imposed Apple embargo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/dear-tech-journalists-please-announce-a-oneyear-selfimposed-apple-embargo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 14:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/dear-tech-journalists-please-announce-a-oneyear-selfimposed-apple-embargo/</guid>
      <description>San Mateo county police, presumably at the bidding of Apple, broke open the front the door of the home of the editor of a technology blog and seized his property. This is in relation to Gizmodo’s revelation of what is presumed to be the next iPhone.
On its merits, Gizmodo may well have broken the law. However, this incident is over a tech gadget, not some explosive device or human trafficking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Facebook: let us define the relationships</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/dear-facebook-let-us-define-the-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 12:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/dear-facebook-let-us-define-the-relationships/</guid>
      <description>We’ve begun implementing some of Facebook’s Open Graph on Alikewise, my dating startup. By Dare Obasanjo’s definition, books are our main “social object”.
(The site is based around the idea that a person will associate themselves with any number of books, with the hope that this will inspire notice by other singles.)
Indeed, the Open Graph protocol is a step toward a more semantic web by allowing us to put agreed-upon metadata into our pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“No carry-on fees” simply means everyone pays carry-on fees</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/no-carryon-fees-simply-means-everyone-pays-carryon-fees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 08:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/no-carryon-fees-simply-means-everyone-pays-carryon-fees/</guid>
      <description>I can’t imagine why Congress is involved in this, but apparently it’s an outrage that airlines are charging fees for carry-on bags.
The fallacy is that by banning such fees, the consumer is saved money. In fact, it’s the opposite.
Since all passengers will be allowed to carry-on without a separate fee, that fee will simply be built into every ticket, regardless of whether the traveler actually takes a carry-on. Instead of no one paying, everyone does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The point at which your project becomes bigger than your head</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-point-at-which-your-project-becomes-bigger-than-your-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 14:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-point-at-which-your-project-becomes-bigger-than-your-head/</guid>
      <description>I’ve seen it argued that a measure of a good programmer is the amount of “stuff” they can keep in their head at one time.
I don’t mean simple memory — I mean that they can retain a larger mental map of what’s going on. They see more of the dependencies and relationships and elements of their project at once, which allows them to write better code and track down issues more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurship and health care</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/entrepreneurship-and-health-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 13:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/entrepreneurship-and-health-care/</guid>
      <description>Some folks are putting forward theories that the new health bill will increase entrepreneurship in the US, as individuals are freed from reliance on large employers for health care. I think the theory is both wishful and unempirical.
The glib (but correct) answer is that, if this were true, Silicon Valley would be in Europe.
The longer answer is that the theory is myopic; it looks at a very small part of the picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The artificial distinction between “content” and “delivery”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-artificial-distinction-between-content-and-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 08:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-artificial-distinction-between-content-and-delivery/</guid>
      <description>In the arguments over net neutrality, the discussion is often around “content” vs “delivery”. The concern is that the delivery people (ISPs) might cut off or otherwise extort the content people. Eg, what if Comcast slowed down YouTube so it could push its own video?
It’s a distinction that exists only in the mind. In the real world, the boundary between content and network is both artificial and fading quickly: …if Google were an ISP it would be the third largest in the world and the fastest growing — if you are measuring the amount of traffic passed from its network to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery appears to be incompatible with IE9 preview</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/jquery-appears-to-be-incompatible-with-ie9-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 13:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/jquery-appears-to-be-incompatible-with-ie9-preview/</guid>
      <description>It would appear that jQuery (1.4.2) is not compatible with the new IE9 preview:
Looks like the .ready() and .live() events are throwing errors. Anyone else?
With IE9’s focus on CSS selectors, I am hoping for some jQuery optimizations — those selectors are a lot like jQ’s so I wonder if a native API will be exposed to use the “native” selector engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t confuse syntax with reasoning</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/dont-confuse-syntax-with-reasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2010 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/dont-confuse-syntax-with-reasoning/</guid>
      <description>This article asks if programming is the new literacy: …we have in a sense returned to the Middle Ages or ancient Egypt, or even before. Then, if you needed to communicate your thoughts on paper, you couldn’t do it yourself. You had to hire a better-educated person — a scribe — who knew the writing code. Then, at the other end, you needed someone to read or decode it — unless, of course, you were “well educated,” that is, you had been taught to read and write and thus had become literate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How about jQuery-style “property methods” for C#?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/how-about-jquerystyle-property-methods-for-c-sharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 21:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/how-about-jquerystyle-property-methods-for-c-sharp/</guid>
      <description>Here’s an idiom that I think would be useful in C#: “property methods” in the style of jQuery.
There are many methods in jQ — html(), val(), width() — that are getters when they are called without an argument, and setters when they are. This makes for some very nice fluent code: $(“#someElement”).width(“100px”).html(“hello there”);
window.alert(“The width of #someElement is ” + $(“#someElement”).width());
I’d love to be able to do this in C#, to bring in some of that fluency and terseness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few more reasons to use Progressive Enhancement</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-few-more-reasons-to-use-progressive-enhancement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 10:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-few-more-reasons-to-use-progressive-enhancement/</guid>
      <description>Progressive Enhancement is a methodology where a web application is developed in layers. Each layer works correctly on its own, and additional layers on top enhance the user experience.
The justifications for Progressive Enhancement are usually around graceful degradation — people using older technologies are not left out in the cold, while better technologies are exploited for more cutting edge users.
Those are fine things, but there are more compelling reasons to use PE, in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net neutrality and preserving the dinosaurs</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/net-neutrality-and-preserving-the-dinosaurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 07:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/net-neutrality-and-preserving-the-dinosaurs/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a chat with a peer/CTO-type who has argued before Congress a local board on net neutrality. Got me thinking again. Even though I made these arguments in the mid 00’s (in a more, um, polemic venue) I thought it might be worth revisiting.
The idea of legislating the flow of bits over the Internet strikes me as saying, we like the Internet the way it is now, please don’t let it change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE8 becomes #1 browser, Chrome up, Firefox plateaus</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/ie8-becomes-sharp1-browser-chrome-up-firefox-plateaus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 09:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/ie8-becomes-sharp1-browser-chrome-up-firefox-plateaus/</guid>
      <description>We have January browser numbers. Firstly, we note that Internet Explorer 8 is now the most popular browser, overtaking IE6.
“Modern browsers”, as previously defined, are now around 60% of the market. Chrome (my fave) gained 0.57 percentage points, which represents a 12% gain in user base.
Firefox stayed approximately even, with a slight downward trend, for the second month in a row.
IE6’s trend of loss leveled off a little bit, to 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google throws down the gauntlet on IE6; you and I get a free ride</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/google-throws-down-the-gauntlet-on-ie6-you-and-i-get-a-free-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 16:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/google-throws-down-the-gauntlet-on-ie6-you-and-i-get-a-free-ride/</guid>
      <description>Today, Google announced that it will begin phasing out support on older browsers, most notably IE6, for Google Docs. It will take this step with Gmail and Calendar later in the year. This is a big step.
There has been much debate about the best way to handle browser obsolescence. On the one had, newer browsers offer a great improvement in user experience and web application capabilities. On the other hand, many people continue to use old browsers, largely because they don’t have other options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Apple emulate the “Kindle everywhere” strategy?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/will-apple-emulate-the-kindle-everywhere-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/will-apple-emulate-the-kindle-everywhere-strategy/</guid>
      <description>I like the concept of e-books, if not their current state-of-the-art. The Kindle device sounds very impressive, I’ve only played with them a bit, and I know they have a lot of devoted fans.
One thing that gets underplayed is that “Kindle” is not simply a device, it’s Amazon’s e-book platform. So instead of spending $300 on the device, I am using the free Kindle for PC application. (There is also an iPhone version but jeez, that’s pushing it in terms of readability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserving the back button on Ajax pages</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/preserving-the-back-button-on-ajax-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 09:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/preserving-the-back-button-on-ajax-pages/</guid>
      <description>So, I’ve been going a little Ajax crazy lately. I am using a progressive enhancement approach — make everything work solidly without Javascript, then drizzle on some Ajaxy goodness as refinement.
One problem is, on an Ajax-driven page, your user “loses” the use of the back button. It’s caused a mismatch between what the user and the browser consider to be a “new page”.
You’ll note that in your Ajax page, when the user clicks to a new “page state”, the URL doesn’t change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modal performance in browsers, or, exploiting z-index</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/modal-performance-in-browsers-or-exploiting-zindex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 13:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/modal-performance-in-browsers-or-exploiting-zindex/</guid>
      <description>I did a little test. I am using jQuery UI’s dialog, and setting it to be draggable. Pretty standard stuff — after all, dragging windows around your computer is commonplace.
A quick look into task manager and I see that dragging that modal around spikes the CPU to around 50%! (And this is with Chrome, an exceptionally fast browser.) Doing the same with a simple Windows file window pushes the CPU to only 10%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breach by design</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/breach-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 09:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/breach-by-design/</guid>
      <description>It appears that the hack against Google was perpetrated via their law enforcement compliance system. As an eminent group of security experts argued in 2008, the trend toward building surveillance capability into telecommunications architecture amounts to a breach-by-design, and a serious security risk. As the volume of requests from law enforcement at all levels grows, the compliance burdens on telcoms grow also — making it increasingly tempting to create automated portals to permit access to user information with minimal human intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google’s China move: don’t be played</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/googles-china-move-dont-be-played/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/googles-china-move-dont-be-played/</guid>
      <description>Hat tip to Sarah Lacy for laying it out so well: Google is ready to burn bridges. This is not how negotiations are done in China, and Google has done well enough there to know that. You don’t get results by pressuring the government in a public, English-language blog post. If Google were indeed still working with the government this letter would not have been posted because it has likely slammed every door shut […] This was a scorched earth move, aimed at buying Google some good will in the rest of the world; Chinese customers and staff were essentially just thrown under the bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netbooks and computer theft</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/netbooks-and-computer-theft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 09:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/netbooks-and-computer-theft/</guid>
      <description>I am sitting in a cafe and a woman is impressed that “this is the kind of place where people leave their computers unattended”, which I guess is true. With the coming age of the netbook, let’s look at the economics of crime.
The what? Yes, the interesting thing here is what happens when a product becomes commoditized, which I define as “cheap enough for just about everyone”. I contend that the emergence of netbooks will essentially end computer theft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone wants to “own the relationship”, until they actually do</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/everyone-wants-to-own-the-relationship-until-they-actually-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/everyone-wants-to-own-the-relationship-until-they-actually-do/</guid>
      <description>It would appear that Google is learning something about customer service: Google is selling the phone directly to end-users. That means many users are turning to it first, and the search giant doesn’t have the kind of customer support that mobile-phone users are accustomed to.[…] Another [customer] using the name SouthFlGuy was also sent back and forth between HTC and T-Mobile after finding no help from Google. “I guess I was under the wrong impression but I thought Google would handle the service on the phone,” he wrote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What follows the “no-fly” list?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-follows-the-nofly-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-follows-the-nofly-list/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we get a foreshadowing of the new, lawless use of the “no-fly” list: Senate Intelligence Chairman Dianne Feinstein, D-Calif., said a “very comprehensive no-fly list” would be “the greatest protection our country has.” In an interview, she said the definition of who can be included should be expanded to include anyone about whom there is “a reasonable suspicion.”
While not exactly house arrest, being on the no-fly list would be enough to severely diminish a person’s economic prospects and quality of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Modern browsers” nearly doubled share in 2009; IE6 lost a third of its user base</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/modern-browsers-nearly-doubled-share-in-2009-ie6-lost-a-third-of-its-user-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/modern-browsers-nearly-doubled-share-in-2009-ie6-lost-a-third-of-its-user-base/</guid>
      <description>So, we have December browser numbers, giving us complete year of browser stats for 2009 [browsers | browser versions]. Here are a few observations.
The year If we consider “modern browsers” to be IE8, Firefox (all versions), Safari (all) and Chrome (all) and Opera (throw ’em a bone), then overall in 2009, the market share for modern browsers increased from 29.5% to 57.0% — nearly double. This is great news: a real majority of web users are now using very capable browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions about the Apple tablet that no one is answering yet</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/questions-about-the-apple-tablet-that-no-one-is-answering-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/questions-about-the-apple-tablet-that-no-one-is-answering-yet/</guid>
      <description>I don’t underestimate Apple’s ability to create unprecedented stuff, and to make it much better than anyone imagined. Yet for all the breathlessness about the supposed Apple tablet, no one seems to be asking the right questions.
First, what problem is it trying to solve? We know what problems laptops and smartphones solve. What’s the tablet solving?
Is it a “third” device? The first device that you are willing to carry is your mobile phone; the second is your laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How about implied interfaces in C#?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/how-about-implied-interfaces-in-c-sharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 18:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/how-about-implied-interfaces-in-c-sharp/</guid>
      <description>I took a look at Google’s new language, Go. Some interesting stuff in there.
One idea in Go that would be especially handy in C# is implied interfaces. What does this mean?
Well, in C# you are accustomed to Interfaces. It’s a description of a type, without an implementation. I won’t go into why they are a good idea (think loose coupling).
A class (aka a Type) is said to satisfy an interface if it includes all the interface’s elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this a good “non-profit” idea?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/is-this-a-good-nonprofit-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/is-this-a-good-nonprofit-idea/</guid>
      <description>So, an idea I have been kicking around a while is BillableHour.org. Would like to gather some feedback.
It’s a simple listing service for those who provide services that are billable by the hour. Such a person (or company) might be a lawyer, a programmer, or a gardener.
The monthly fee for listing on the site is your hourly rate. The proceeds go to a variety of charities, probably voted on by participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmers and “productivity”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/programmers-and-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2009 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/programmers-and-productivity/</guid>
      <description>There have been some interesting posts lately asking the question, “if some programmers are 10 times as productive as others, why aren’t they paid 10 times as much?”. It’s a good question, though I don’t think the recent posts quite get to the heart of it.
Some have said that it’s a sociological thing — that we, as a culture, generally don’t accept great disparities in pay. Within a mediocre organization, that might be true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T etc etc</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/att-etc-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 20:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/att-etc-etc/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T etc etc According to Gizmodo, AT&amp;amp;T comes out #1 for data performance. My interest is two-fold. First, I get a geek thrill is watching networks getting built. Second, I have a pet peeve about the whole AT&amp;amp;T-hating thing lately.
I really don’t care about loving or hating any particular company, and I find it so strange that others do. I think the ratio of people who are complaining about AT&amp;amp;T, versus those that are having measurable issues, is about 100:1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing mission creep in your Views, or, ignorance is bliss</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/preventing-mission-creep-in-your-views-or-ignorance-is-bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2009 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/preventing-mission-creep-in-your-views-or-ignorance-is-bliss/</guid>
      <description>An important concept in MVC is that Views are meant to be “dumb” — and by that I mean, your View should only care about outputting a user interface, and should know very little about business logic.
You want this for a few reasons. For example, you might create alternate Views for different kinds of output, such as for a mobile device. You shouldn’t have to re-implement any business logic to do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Man sticks it to The Man; or, the Country-club Revolt; or, Whitey’s Revenge</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-man-sticks-it-to-the-man-or-the-countryclub-revolt-or-whiteys-revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 21:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-man-sticks-it-to-the-man-or-the-countryclub-revolt-or-whiteys-revenge/</guid>
      <description>So Fake Steve, who I like, thinks it would be funny to try to overload AT&amp;amp;T network tomorrow. Which, fine, OK, but consider this.
This would be an act by a bunch of well-to-do people (the iPhone costs over $2000 over the life of your contract) against a bunch of other well-to-do people. You’re not sticking it to The Man; you are The Man.
You’re in a friggin’ chair in the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Resig jQuery talk</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/john-resig-jquery-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 09:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/john-resig-jquery-talk/</guid>
      <description>Very interesting (if-you’re-a-nerd) talk by John Resig. It’s real geek stuff but the takeaways are:
 John is very serious about testing, tracing and benchmarking for jQuery (and frameworks in general). For you and me, that means faster, more reliable jQuery. Win. (He also thinks many common benchmarks are bullshit not statistically sound.) jQuery 1.4 takes advantage of the above. He approaches performance more in terms of reducing complexity, as opposed to tweaking optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tegra notebooks wanted</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/tegra-notebooks-wanted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/tegra-notebooks-wanted/</guid>
      <description>I would love to see notebooks based on Nvidia’s insane Tegra chip:
The above can drive 720p HDMI output from a friggin’ handheld. The Zune HD uses one. So why not a notebook?
A friend recently got a netbook as a gift, and it’s cool, and it gets like 10 hours of battery life, but it’s way slow. Shouldn’t your notebook be as powerful as your handheld? Shouldn’t it run video without breaking a sweat, as the iPhone does?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up localhost in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/speeding-up-localhost-in-visual-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 11:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/speeding-up-localhost-in-visual-studio/</guid>
      <description>I recently put a new SSD in my system (yay!) and did a clean install of Windows 7, Visual Studio, etc. I found that when viewing my web app on localhost (using the Cassini web server built into VS), it was very slow. This was true across browsers.
Turns out it’s a DNS thing — the lookup for “localhost” was apparently going out to the DNS server, a waste. You can easily “short-circuit” this by modifying your hosts file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon’s core competency? Pricing.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/amazons-core-competency-pricing./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/amazons-core-competency-pricing./</guid>
      <description>I think it’s quite brilliant that Amazon has introduced spot pricing for servers. Great way to exploit unutilized CPUs and bring prices down. Nicholas Carr explains it in utility terms: At the end of the nineteenth century, Samuel Insull, president of the then-tiny Chicago Edison, started the electric utility revolution when he had the counterintuitive realization that to make more money his company had to cut its prices drastically, at least for those customers whose patterns of electricity use would help the utility maximize its capacity utilization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wi-fi cafes in NYC</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/wifi-cafes-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 10:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/wifi-cafes-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>I’ve begun compiling a list of wi-fi cafes in New York City, with a bias toward those in my neighborhood. Hope it helps, and let me know of your finds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100% data loss at Coding Horror??</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/100-percent-data-loss-at-coding-horror/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/100-percent-data-loss-at-coding-horror/</guid>
      <description>This can’t be good:
Can servers really fail that spectacularly? I mean, yes of course they can but something running on RAID 5 should be recoverable. For this to happen, it would require a lot of neglect plus a healthy dose of bad luck. Yikes.
h/t Hacker News</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shorting Firefox</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/shorting-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 09:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/shorting-firefox/</guid>
      <description>If Firefox were a stock, I’d be shorting it. That’s what I said a few months ago, too, and one of the Mozilla guys took issue.
I’ll say it again: what Firefox has is a user base, not a future. It’s not unlike Microsoft right now — their success is based on momentum, not new converts. (If Microsoft and Apple were to emerge from the womb today, who would win?)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schneier and Schmidt</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/schneier-and-schmidt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 08:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/schneier-and-schmidt/</guid>
      <description>Schmidt: if you’re not doing anything wrong, you have no need for privacy
Schneier: that’s not what privacy is for
Guess whose side I am on. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser-specific CSS without Javascript or horrible syntax</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/browserspecific-css-without-javascript-or-horrible-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 03:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/browserspecific-css-without-javascript-or-horrible-syntax/</guid>
      <description>So, we all know that browsers have differing levels of CSS support. Working around them can be a pain in the a**, requiring non-standards-based hacks which are very hard to read and debug.
I’d like to write CSS that looks like this:
.ie div.thing
{
…some tweaks for IE…
}
.ff div.thing
{
…some tweaks for Firefox…
}
…etc. Even better:
.ie6 div.thing
{
…curse you old browser…
}
That’s readable, and isn’t polluted with the –moz stuff or &amp;lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logic as data, and a case where strong typing impeded learning</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/logic-as-data-and-a-case-where-strong-typing-impeded-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2009 11:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/logic-as-data-and-a-case-where-strong-typing-impeded-learning/</guid>
      <description>These days, I am doing a lot of Javascript, or more accurately, a lot of jQuery. A concept I have gotten comfortable with is the idea of passing logic as data.
This article demonstrates a pattern to avoid brittle if-then statements. Instead of very long conditional branches, one encapsulates evaluation logic in a table of data. Each data item is a function containing an arbitrary piece of logic — code which runs after being passed to the main algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{less} CSS for .Net</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/less-css-for-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/less-css-for-.net/</guid>
      <description>A while back I asked whether some enterprising-person-who-is-smarter-than-I would offer a version of the {less} CSS framework for .Net. Looks like they have, and they did it as I’d hoped: an HttpHandler mapped to the .less extension. So your .less files are compiled on the fly and served to the browser as plain ol’ CSS.
In brief, {less} is a syntax for CSS that allows for programmability and reusability. Define a color (or a whole set of CSS properties) in one place, and refer to them throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gold mine for StackOverflow</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-gold-mine-for-stackoverflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-gold-mine-for-stackoverflow/</guid>
      <description>This is a gold mine for Joel and Jeff over at StackOverflow: careers. It’s something I thought of a while ago, and I am sure the SO guys were ahead of me by a millennium.
I think of markets in two main ways: robustness of information, and incentives.
On the information side, all the people who use StackOverflow have a great way to demonstrate their knowledge (or lack thereof). If an employer is interested in a candidate, they can view a (hopefully rich) history of their questions and answers to specific problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betting on a future without IE6</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/betting-on-a-future-without-ie6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 20:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/betting-on-a-future-without-ie6/</guid>
      <description>My startup is developing a new web site, and every web developer must decide the extent to which they will support old technology — especially Internet Explorer 6.
From a technology perspective, officially supporting that browser could mean forgoing sexy features, or spending an inordinate amount of time working around the browser’s limitations and inconsistencies. You want your devs to spend their time making your site more compelling.
On the other hand, there are a lot of customers on IE6 whom you don’t want to alienate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Intel having so much trouble shipping its solid-state drives?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/why-is-intel-having-so-much-trouble-shipping-its-solidstate-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 09:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/why-is-intel-having-so-much-trouble-shipping-its-solidstate-drives/</guid>
      <description>I know I am getting repetitive but I have to ask again — why is Intel having so much trouble shipping its second-generation solid-state drives (the X25-M G2)?
A look around the web reveals that supplies are extremely constrained or non-existent. Amazon shows not in stock. NewEgg is sold out. Other smaller sellers at Amazon are showing inventory, but at prices well above MSRP — this indicates that these sellers are probably grasping at 1 or 2 units at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizards in ASP.Net MVC: being selective with ModelState</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/wizards-in-asp.net-mvc-being-selective-with-modelstate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 21:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/wizards-in-asp.net-mvc-being-selective-with-modelstate/</guid>
      <description>So, there are many ways to skin the cat we called form validation. With a wizard-style application, it requires some nuance.
With ASP.Net MVC, a traditional way to do validation is to use ModelState. ModelState is a property on your controller where you can collect errors relating to your Model. For example, if a LastName property is required, you would do something like this:
if (String.IsNullOrEmpty(lastName))
ModelState.AddModelError(“lastName”, “A last name is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Microsoft Ajax Minifier, some gotcha’s</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/using-the-microsoft-ajax-minifier-some-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 15:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/using-the-microsoft-ajax-minifier-some-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>I am playing with the Microsoft Ajax Minifier, which removes whitespace from your Javascripts for quicker download. Stephen Walther has a nice how-to.
In my case, I am using the MSBuild task, which will minimize your Javascripts on build. Works great on my machine. But here’s the gotcha: if you have a build server that does not have the Minifier installed, your build will fail.
What to do? In my case, I updated Stephen’s MSBuild code with a Condition such that the task will only run under the Debug configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsolicited iPhone suggestions #2: internet radio</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/unsolicited-iphone-suggestions-sharp2-internet-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 09:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/unsolicited-iphone-suggestions-sharp2-internet-radio/</guid>
      <description>Since moving from Cali to NY, I’ve come to miss my favorite radio station, KDFC. They rule, especially Hoyt Smith on my clock radio in the morning.
So I stream it via iTunes on the PC. Sounds great even if I can’t wake up to it.
But the iPhone doesn’t do Internet radio easily. It has the capability of streaming audio, but only through a roundabout process or some unintuitive app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTF Intel?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/wtf-intel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 09:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/wtf-intel/</guid>
      <description>One would think, after announcing the product in July, that Intel might be shipping its next-gen solid state hard drives. One would be wrong.
I think one of the biggest uses of these drives will be to resuscitate old machines that would otherwise be tossed. A four-year-old CPU is still faster than what most people need, but if you swap out the slowest part of the machine (the disk), you might find you have a perfectly good netbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yup, Microsoft is focusing on Javascript</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/yup-microsoft-is-focusing-on-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 12:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/yup-microsoft-is-focusing-on-javascript/</guid>
      <description>So Microsoft announced IE9 today, and yes they are looking at probably a big Javascript performance increase, like I figured.
Video:
A chart:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone calendar has a separate time zone from the phone</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-iphone-calendar-has-a-separate-time-zone-from-the-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 18:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-iphone-calendar-has-a-separate-time-zone-from-the-phone/</guid>
      <description>After my recent move to NYC, I discovered that my Google Calendar was 3 hours off from my iPhone calendar. No worries, just go into the iPhone Settings — General — Date &amp;amp; Time and make sure the phone understands the time zone. Huh, well, it’s set automatically, over the air.
There is a setting in Google Calendar for time zone. Changed that. No joy.
Finally, I looked deep into the iPhone’s Mail, Contacts and Calendar settings — and way at the bottom of that screen, you set the time zone for the calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE9 preview coming?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/ie9-preview-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 17:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/ie9-preview-coming/</guid>
      <description>Rumors of an IE9 announcement. Let’s find out if my predictions are correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>keyCode vs charCode vs Firefox</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/keycode-vs-charcode-vs-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 15:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/keycode-vs-charcode-vs-firefox/</guid>
      <description>I am working on a filtered HTML field. The idea is to only allow alphanumeric characters to be typed, and have all other keystrokes ignored.
I am using the keypress event in jQuery to capture the keystrokes — my function returns true for valid characters (which simply passes the event to the field) and false for everything else (which kills the event before it can “reach” the field).
The behavior was fine in IE and Chrome, but not in Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsolicited iPhone suggestions #1: email</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/unsolicited-iphone-suggestions-sharp1-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 12:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/unsolicited-iphone-suggestions-sharp1-email/</guid>
      <description>OK, so a friend is raving about his Droid phone, and it sounds quite cool. The Palm Pre has some good ideas too. Hopefully a little competition will keep Apple from being Apple — “we know what’s best for you” — too often.
So, a few things that would dramatically improve the email experience on the iPhone, for this humble user anyway.
 Unified email view: Allow me to see all my email messages, from multiple accounts, in one list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The emergence of Big Data (2.0)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-emergence-of-big-data-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 10:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-emergence-of-big-data-2.0/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written previously on the idea that data, not algorithms, will be a main differentiator for web companies moving forward. What does this mean?
In short, it’s not hard to hire very smart people to write algorithms. One or two PhD’s can produce a lot of great logic. But algorithms need data — big data — to be useful, and that’s considerably harder to amass. Only a small number of firms will have it, and it will represent a barrier to entry that nimble startups can’t climb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teevee on the peecee</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/teevee-on-the-peecee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 11:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/teevee-on-the-peecee/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve moved to a new place in NYC, and it’s a bit…cozier…than what I was used to in San Francisco. So I am looking for ways to save space and for now I’ve decided to go without a TV.
I do like TV, I admit. So am cobbling together a few ways to watch shows without paying for cable or buying another screen.
I’ve found that the state of television on the computer is still a bit DIY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google music previews songs based on lyrics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/google-music-previews-songs-based-on-lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 09:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/google-music-previews-songs-based-on-lyrics/</guid>
      <description>Neat, if you type in a partial lyric to a song — without even referring to the title or artist — Google finds it and gives it to you to play right there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Closure based on naive server-side notions?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/google-closure-based-on-naive-serverside-notions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 09:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/google-closure-based-on-naive-serverside-notions/</guid>
      <description>I rely on libraries (mostly jQuery) instead of writing a lot of serious JavaScript these days. I mean, of course I am writing JavaScript but the libraries allow me to stay in “script space” — small procedure bits that are scripts as opposed to applications.
But I do like to keep an eye on best practices, and this article offers some great tips from an experienced JS library developer.
He offers them in the context of ripping Google’s new Closure library — he says it’s evident that it was done by Java people without much real-world JavaScript experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows virtual machines get competitive</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/windows-virtual-machines-get-competitive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/windows-virtual-machines-get-competitive/</guid>
      <description>Rackspace has announced that they are getting into the Windows virtual machine bizness. I’ve been waiting for this market to heat up, and have competition drive down some prices.
RAM is everything, and the service providers usually make this the main spec you pay for. In virtual environments, it’s even more important since disk I/O tends to be especially slow — you want to keep as much in RAM as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new language from Google</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-new-language-from-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 17:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-new-language-from-google/</guid>
      <description>Neat, Google has a new language called Go. Clever branding, that.
It seems to be Google’s attempt to step into the Java/C# space. Perhaps I don’t know enough about languages to make such an assertion, but the thing that clued me in was its type safety. That seems decidedly untrendy.
Google seems to have stepped over a basic OO concept: inheritance. Smart C# programmers know to use interfaces instead of inheritance, where possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Paris Hilton problem</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-paris-hilton-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 07:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-paris-hilton-problem/</guid>
      <description>Joel Spolsky has an article in Inc describing the tension between growth and quality at his company. The issue is, if your competitor is outgrowing you, their dominance might become self-fulfilling: customers prefer a safe choice, and the safe choice is what other customers are buying. Even if your product is better, nothing attracts a crowd like a crowd.
Your competitor begins to look like Paris Hilton: famous for being famous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The flagship strategy of mobile phones — Microsoft needs one</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-flagship-strategy-of-mobile-phones-microsoft-needs-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-flagship-strategy-of-mobile-phones-microsoft-needs-one/</guid>
      <description>The flagship strategy of mobile phones — Microsoft needs one In the wake of the iPhone over the last few years, it seems that the market is responding to a business model different than the PC’s that preceded it. Mobile phones seem to require a very tight integration of hardware and software (and arguably service) to make a splash.
Apple fans will say, “Well, duh!”. But Apple lost the PC battle for 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Apple treading water with the Apple TV? Because the real product is in the works.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/why-is-apple-treading-water-with-the-apple-tv-because-the-real-product-is-in-the-works./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/why-is-apple-treading-water-with-the-apple-tv-because-the-real-product-is-in-the-works./</guid>
      <description>Apple has come out with version 3.0 of its Apple TV product, and it appears to be little more than a visual refresh with a couple of nice bits of iTunes integration. It still doesn’t do what we expect of a “set-top box” or “media center”: things like recording live TV.
The Apple TV is proving that it does not belong in those categories of hardware above. It’s more correct to think of it as an iTunes extender — an elegant way to get your movies and music onto the TV, assuming that iTunes is your starting point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE6 users and status-conscious creative directors</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/ie6-users-and-statusconscious-creative-directors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 01:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/ie6-users-and-statusconscious-creative-directors/</guid>
      <description>A friend directed me to this site , belonging to a creative director at Squarespace, and containing the following message for IE6 users: Hi, if you are coming to this site via Internet Explorer 6, you might not be getting the best experience possible. Honestly, I can’t even begin to think about what your entire experience on the internet must be like? (…probably like riding a bike on the highway while cars blow by you on their way to Costco to get gallons of mayonnaise and 60-inch plasma TV’s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does this metric pass the smell test?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/does-this-metric-pass-the-smell-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 00:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/does-this-metric-pass-the-smell-test/</guid>
      <description>Via Silicon Alley Insider, an analysis by a company called Drake Direct claims that 1 in 4 pageviews in the US goes to Facebook.
Hmm. I don’t doubt that Facebook gets a truly enormous amount of traffic. But 25% of the Internet? This must be some sort of derivative or artificial metric. It’s not 1 of 4 of mine. I know a handful of people that might reach that percentage — but then that number of people represents only a sample of heavily-engaged users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Apple fix Boot Camp for Windows?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/will-apple-fix-boot-camp-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/will-apple-fix-boot-camp-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>I wrote earlier about how Windows running on Mac hardware via Boot Camp appears to have serious battery-life issues — getting only around 2 hours of life on a machine that should offer at least twice that.
I speculated there was some sort of proprietary DRM-ish hardware layer that Windows was fighting against, but commenters thought that that the ACPI power profile that Apple offers is not sufficient. In any case, it seems consistent across all Windows versions on Mac hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>California says the iPhone costs $599</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/california-says-the-iphone-costs-599/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 12:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/california-says-the-iphone-costs-599/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased a new iPhone 3GS since my previous phone bit the dust (or pavement, more accurately). I went to order online via AT&amp;amp;T, and was surprised to find out the tax on a $199 phone was $56, or over 25%. Wha? I went to make the same purchase at Apple’s online store, and found the same thing.
Then I decided to just mosey down to the nearby (physical) Apple store — and of course the tax was the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Verizon’s network better, or is it simply untested?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/is-verizons-network-better-or-is-it-simply-untested/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 15:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/is-verizons-network-better-or-is-it-simply-untested/</guid>
      <description>This article over a TechCrunch is putatively about the iPhone, but the take-away for me is that AT&amp;amp;T’s data traffic has grown 50-fold over the last 3 years:
(Slide is by Mary Meeker of Morgan Stanley)
It’s easy to complain about AT&amp;amp;T’s network, etc, because people like to bitch. But I am not aware of any data service that has ever scaled up that quickly.
And one wonders what Verizon’s aggregate data traffic looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla VP: “mistakes were made”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/mozilla-vp-mistakes-were-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/mozilla-vp-mistakes-were-made/</guid>
      <description>I love the language of Mozilla VP Mike Shaver’s non-retraction retraction regarding a Microsoft plugin for Firefox: We received confirmation from Microsoft this evening that the Framework Assistant add-on is not a mechanism for exploiting the vulnerabilities detailed in the earlier post, so we’ve removed it from the blocklist.
Hee hee. In other words, there was not a security vulnerability, although we stated unequivocally that there was, and others quickly parroted same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word nerdism #1: Make mine a medium</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/word-nerdism-sharp1-make-mine-a-medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 01:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/word-nerdism-sharp1-make-mine-a-medium/</guid>
      <description>I am a word nerd, I love crosswords and love to wonder how words and expressions come to be. I also love thinking about computer languages as languages, with style and grammar. (For example, see the interplay between terseness and readability.)
I got to thinking about the word medium. We talk about medium as in, I’ll have a medium soda. We also talk about media like radio and television. Different meanings, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think of SSDs as multi-core storage</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/think-of-ssds-as-multicore-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2009 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/think-of-ssds-as-multicore-storage/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a few times why solid-state hard drives (SSDs) are a sea change, similar to our transition from CRT to LCD a few years ago.
Anandtech gets it right in an exhaustive analysis of why this is so. The biggest problem with traditional (spinning) hard drives is not simply raw speed — it’s that they are sequential.
Many traditional drives can do high-throughput when you benchmark them. And that’s all well and good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StackOverflow == Facebook * .0001</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/stackoverflow-facebook-.0001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/stackoverflow-facebook-.0001/</guid>
      <description>Apparently, Facebook is running around 30,000 physical servers. That hurts my head. With 300,000,000 users, that translates to around 10,000 users per server. They are doing (back-of-the-envelope) ~4.2 billion pageviews/day. Each server, then, is doing around 140,000 page views per day.
What Facebook is doing is especially hard: nearly every page that you view on the site is generated fresh just for you, and needs to know about new changes from any one of your dozens or hundreds of friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving the n&#43;1 problem in Linq to SQL, using projection</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/solving-the-n1-problem-in-linq-to-sql-using-projection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 16:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/solving-the-n1-problem-in-linq-to-sql-using-projection/</guid>
      <description>Rick Strahl has a nice solution for mitigating the n+1 problem in Linq to SQL. The n+1 problem is a situation where, as you iterate over a set of query results in a list view, one or more additional database queries are fired for each row in the list. Since database calls are relatively expensive, you want to keep these to a minimum.
Things like Linq to SQL make this an easy mistake to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple way that Apple can improve iPhone battery life and user experience</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-simple-way-that-apple-can-improve-iphone-battery-life-and-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 12:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-simple-way-that-apple-can-improve-iphone-battery-life-and-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>I dig my iPhone, but when I switched over from my Blackberry, I was very surprised at how many steps it takes to find out about new email.
On the Blackberry, there is an external light that flashes a different color based on new messages. Then, when you log in to the BB home screen, the Messages icon has a little badge indicating new messages, also by color. So either one or zero interactions is enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Apple aligns with a carrier, act II</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/when-apple-aligns-with-a-carrier-act-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/when-apple-aligns-with-a-carrier-act-ii/</guid>
      <description>Apple is not really a partnering company. They make their own hardware and software — and services like .Mac Mobile Me — to ensure a certain user experience. This is their offer, and it works.
When Apple partnered with AT&amp;amp;T to release the iPhone, this was an unusual ceding of control on Apple’s part. They couldn’t build a phone network, of course, and that business is probably a bit old-school and low-margin for stylie Apple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A thought experiment: serial vs parallel</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-thought-experiment-serial-vs-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 18:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-thought-experiment-serial-vs-parallel/</guid>
      <description>Now that solid-state drives are arriving in the mainstream, I’ve been thinking about the implications of serial vs parallel and how they affect overall perceived performance. And by “perceived” I mean, what does the client — both the technical and human variety — experience?
If the capacity of two systems is each (say) ten requests per hour, yet one is serial and one is parallel, can there be a net benefit for the user?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compile-time checking of views in ASP.Net MVC</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/compiletime-checking-of-views-in-asp.net-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 15:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/compiletime-checking-of-views-in-asp.net-mvc/</guid>
      <description>I noticed that syntax errors in my views were not being caught during the build process — instead I would find them at run-time when I actually hit the view.
This struck me as odd — certainly one would want to know about compilation errors at compile-time, no?
So I emailed ScottGu and he directed me to this helpful tip, with will do exactly the above:
http://devermind.com/aspnet/aspnet-mvc-tip-turn-on-compile-time-view-checking/
Scott (and the author of the above) warn that this will slow down builds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your bottleneck is you, or, why I’ve stopped worrying about performance</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/your-bottleneck-is-you-or-why-ive-stopped-worrying-about-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/your-bottleneck-is-you-or-why-ive-stopped-worrying-about-performance/</guid>
      <description>Provocative headline, no? Let me explain.
Like Jeff Atwood, I consider end-user performance to be a feature. Pages should snap. It sends a very positive signal to customers, IMHO. And the site should snap with 10 or 10,000 users.
That said, as a developer I am learning to worry less about the little things when it comes to performance.
For example, I went to a SQL Server talk where they worried about how many disk spindles to split the load across.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dullest blog</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-dullest-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-dullest-blog/</guid>
      <description>I navigated on my computer to the web site called “The dullest blog in the world”. I was mildly amused for several minutes. After which, I visited other web sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Google building an anti-spam empire?, or, size matters</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/is-google-building-an-antispam-empire-or-size-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/is-google-building-an-antispam-empire-or-size-matters/</guid>
      <description>Google acquired reCAPTCHA today, a company that provides a simple means of adding a spam-limiting mechanism to your site. (I’ve implemented it several times and I recommend it to clients.)
There are technologies where size matters more than others. One of them is spam-fighting.
Spam, whether in email or in the comments of a blog, is fought with data. It is a statistical game — lots of very fast computers doing their best to ask, how much does this message resemble spam?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the heck is going on with Intel’s next-generation SSDs?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-the-heck-is-going-on-with-intels-nextgeneration-ssds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 17:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-the-heck-is-going-on-with-intels-nextgeneration-ssds/</guid>
      <description>Intel first announced its second generation consumer solid-state drives on July 21. There were plenty of positive reviews at the time, and the price drop combined with better performance made me ready to take the plunge.
A few days later, a defect was found. Intel has historically done a good job of issuing patches, so I assumed that a firmware fix would not be a big deal. But then they disappeared from store shelves (by which I mean e-tailers like Amazon and NewEgg).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickie geek quiz #4</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 10:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp4/</guid>
      <description>For fabulous prizes, or perhaps a hearty attaboy, the question is:
People are throwing things at you and yelling “horn high yo”. Who are you, and what are they asking you to do?
No Googling! Honor system. Please answer in the comments below.
(I gotta disqualify Fernando, Joe and Matt M on this one. I know they know the answer.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying an ASP.net MVC project</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/deploying-an-asp.net-mvc-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 17:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/deploying-an-asp.net-mvc-project/</guid>
      <description>So, I was looking around for a simple way to emulate the “Publish” function of Visual Studio for my first ASP.net MVC project.
I am doing my builds on a server with CruiseControl.Net. Google led me to things like msdeploy, which I am sure is great, but really I shouldn’t need another tool.
I need two steps implemented as simply as possible:
 Build it Move the built project to directory that IIS points to — but only the required files  The build step is straightforward and familiar to those who use CC: the MsBuild Task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale means reversing your thinking on the database</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/scale-means-reversing-your-thinking-on-the-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 19:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/scale-means-reversing-your-thinking-on-the-database/</guid>
      <description>There are only a small number of sites in the world that require truly tremendous scale. Usually, this is referred to as “web scale”, and describes a site where the data is user-generated and highly dynamic. Among the first that come to mind are Facebook, Digg, MySpace and the like.
Once you get to that scale, the rules of building a site become counter-intuitive to what most of us know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “var” thing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-var-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 11:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-var-thing/</guid>
      <description>I’ve come to really enjoy using the “var” keyword in C#. Although it’s been written about many times, I want to clarify what it is.
C# is a strongly-typed language, which means that every variable you declare must have a specified type. You must say it’s an integer or a string or a Thing. “var” does not change that.
“var” looks a lot like the var in Javascript. Javascript is not strongly-typed, so you don’t have to say what “x” represents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the word…?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/whats-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/whats-the-word/</guid>
      <description>Oh right…bollocks. This report seems to be circulating that “Braidwood”, Intel’s inexpensive flash-memory-disk-cache-helper-outer, will somehow negate demand for full-blown SSDs (solid-state drives).
Bollocks. Sure, Braidwood sounds like it might be useful but it’s a wedge. It’s a shim. It’s a little add-on that will offer a nice incremental performance boost for a few dollars.
SSDs, in my opinion, are a sea change that’s waiting to happen. They are about 10x faster than the “spinning rust” that comprises a traditional hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I heart jQuery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/why-i-heart-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 21:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/why-i-heart-jquery/</guid>
      <description>I am one of the many people who have fallen in love with jQuery over the past year or two. I haven’t seen it articulated why this might be, so here’s my stab at it.
Many programmers I know are server-oriented. They consider dealing with HTML and Javascript a chore. Those client-side things are sloppy, loose and hard to predict. We patch them together as best we can, and cross fingers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickie geek quiz #3</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2009 13:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp3/</guid>
      <description>Alright, today’s geek question relates to branding:
Which company trademarked the brand name “Heroin”?
Bonus: under what circumstances did they lose that trademark?
No Googling! Honor system ‘round here. Answer in the comments.
—
A couple of hints. Happened over 100 years ago. The company invented and owned the trademark for another common drug that’s sitting in your medicine cabinet right now, and lost that trademark for the same reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s the data, not the algorithm</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/its-the-data-not-the-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 21:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/its-the-data-not-the-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Chris Dixon points out that the challenge in “artificial intelligence” — which in a mainstream definition would be “making computers learn like humans” — is not so much the cleverness of the algorithm but in finding useful data. He cites the Google example where the breakthrough was realizing that links are a good (and previously untapped) source of data on what people think is a relevant web page. Modern AI algorithms are very powerful, but the reality is there are thousands of programmers/researchers who can implement them with about the same level of success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barber shop recommendation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/barber-shop-recommendation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/barber-shop-recommendation/</guid>
      <description>Tech blogging shall resume shortly.
So, it was 90+ degrees in NY and I went for a run. I’ve never perspired that much in my life. On the walk back to where I was staying, I stopped in a barber shop and said “how much to take it off”?
$16. Wow, that’s cheap. The place did a proper job and even shaved my neck with a straight blade.
They’re called Reamir and apparently they have several locations in Manhattan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickie geek quiz #2</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp2/</guid>
      <description>OK, I might or might not give out a prize like last time. Times are tight, y’know. Impress me and we’ll see. The question is:
What is the difference between a meteor and a meteorite?
Bonus points for describing what the term “meteor” refers to, precisely.
No Googling! Honor system. Please answer in the comments.
—
Update: Russ is a winner! I believe that meteor specifically refers to the streak of light in the sky, as opposed to the object itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chair in the sky</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/chair-in-the-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 08:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/chair-in-the-sky/</guid>
      <description>In a few years this will seem quaint, but I am posting this from 30,000 feet. Gogo wi-fi on Virgin America, it actually seems to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Microsoft “subsidize” Zune HD pricing?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/will-microsoft-subsidize-zune-hd-pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/will-microsoft-subsidize-zune-hd-pricing/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft announced pricing for its upcoming Zune HD today, coming around 25% below the prices of equivalent iPod Touches. I wondered if Microsoft is making any money at such prices — after all, it’s based on a fancy new chip and has other nice specs.
Then it occurred to me that perhaps Microsoft has room to lose money on the hardware. If customers buy the Zune subscription music service, MS will be taking in around $15/mo after the initial sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tell me your favorite expression for “dead”</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/tell-me-your-favorite-expression-for-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/tell-me-your-favorite-expression-for-dead/</guid>
      <description>I was amused by this article’s title. So I’ve decided to compile clever expressions for “dead”. Tell me your faves in the comments below. I’ll update this page with the best ones.
 Barefoot on Abbey Road (explanation)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Killer app for the Zune HD: Tivo for radio</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/killer-app-for-the-zune-hd-tivo-for-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/killer-app-for-the-zune-hd-tivo-for-radio/</guid>
      <description>The upcoming Zune HD sounds pretty nice. I use my iPhone less as a recorded music device and more like a radio. I listen to podcasts or Pandora. Honestly, in the age of subscription media I have no interest in buying-and-syncing music.
Unlike the iPhone, the new Zune will come with an HD Radio tuner. Here’s the opportunity.
I’d love it if my Zune recorded radio like a Tivo. When I go out for a run, or get on the plane, I can just browse whatever has been queued up — or listen live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickie geek quiz #1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/quickie-geek-quiz-sharp1/</guid>
      <description>OK, $10 on iTunes or Amazon for the first person to answer this:
What keyword in C# is derived from a person’s name, and who is that person?
Answer in the comments below or via Twitter.
—
Update: solved! Congrats Paolo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Google going to do with On2?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-is-google-going-to-do-with-on2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 22:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-is-google-going-to-do-with-on2/</guid>
      <description>Google recently acquired On2, a company that creates video codecs, most notably for Flash (which is used on the most popular video sites). Dan Rayburn runs down and debunks a number of theories as to what Google has in mind. Rightly, he says that none are obviously correct.
(Side note, I’ve used On2’s Flix products for some time.)
I don’t think Google has an immediate tactical goal with the acquisition. They are delivering video just fine without owning the technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random numbers web service</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/random-numbers-web-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 21:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/random-numbers-web-service/</guid>
      <description>Generating numbers that are truly random is quite difficult. Every random number needs to be based on some starting place — the time of day in milliseconds, perhaps. As such it’s actually a predictable number; it’s deterministic, even if a regular human won’t realistically guess it.
For most of what we do, we create a pseudo-random number — one that is random enough for our purposes. Yet I’ve experienced situations where the “pseudo” part becomes very apparent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The most viable reason for Apple’s rejection of Google Voice (so far)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-most-viable-reason-for-apples-rejection-of-google-voice-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 12:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-most-viable-reason-for-apples-rejection-of-google-voice-so-far/</guid>
      <description>So, in the Apple-Google-AT&amp;amp;T kerfuffle over Google Voice being rejected from the iPhone, I haven’t heard many reasons I consider viable. This one is: I’ve been asking myself exactly why Apple or AT&amp;amp;T would stir up the hornet’s nest to deny the technology and risk the ire of both the government and one of their most valuable partners, and also why each company’s stance is full of contradictory actions.After a little reflection, the answer became resoundingly clear: Apple is building a similar service to add to MobileMe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you have “grit”?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/do-you-have-grit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2009 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/do-you-have-grit/</guid>
      <description>A very interesting study of the idea of “grit”. It attempts to quantify personal characteristics than lead to success via perseverance.
I often wonder if I have it. I am willing to take risks which depend on my intelligence — I quit my job to start a startup. But I really fear that I’ve gotten soft.
I get bored easily; this is the opposite of grit. So perhaps those who have “grit” are the ones who have found a way to feel rewarded even when the work is boring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A market opportunity for Verizon and Sprint</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-market-opportunity-for-verizon-and-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-market-opportunity-for-verizon-and-sprint/</guid>
      <description>In the current FCC-involved kerfuffle over why Apple or AT&amp;amp;T blocked Google Voice on the iPhone, I see opportunity.
I am not convinced that AT&amp;amp;T is the reason for blocking the app. It certainly could be, but from a technical perspective, a Google Voice call is the same as an AT&amp;amp;T call. It doesn’t strain their network.
The only person to touch on a plausible explanation is Michael Arrington who notes that number portability is the real bugaboo from AT&amp;amp;T’s perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>403 Forbidden (and 400 Bad Request) errors with Amazon Product Advertising API</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/403-forbidden-and-400-bad-request-errors-with-amazon-product-advertising-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 16:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/403-forbidden-and-400-bad-request-errors-with-amazon-product-advertising-api/</guid>
      <description>I recently experienced an issue using the Amazon Product Advertising API (formerly the Amazon Associates Web Service). I was getting a “403 Forbidden” error for what seemed like a normal request.
I am using the sample C# code provided here, along with the Amazon.ECS library (which apparently is no longer supported by Amazon).
I was doing an ItemSearchRequest, with a search term of “black swan”.
I tracked the error down to the encoding of the search terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is proprietary Mac hardware killing Windows battery life?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/is-proprietary-mac-hardware-killing-windows-battery-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/is-proprietary-mac-hardware-killing-windows-battery-life/</guid>
      <description>Dong Ngo over at CNET has a review of the experience of installing the final Windows 7 on a new (unibody) MacBook Pro.
The install works. However, the battery life is awful: What’s missing has been a known issue with Mac laptop running Boot Camp: the battery life. According to Apple, the MacBook Pro offers about eight hours of battery life (in my experience it’s more like about five hours, which is still very impressive).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Someone please sell me a solid-state drive with Windows 7 on it</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/someone-please-sell-me-a-solidstate-drive-with-windows-7-on-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 10:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/someone-please-sell-me-a-solidstate-drive-with-windows-7-on-it/</guid>
      <description>The thing that computers are good at is brainless repetition. They are perfect when you’ve figured out a logical problem and need to exploit it over and over.
In programming, we achieve this with encapsulation and abstraction. If we have 100 gifts to wrap, we could write:
 ChooseWrappingPaper() Go to Walgreens Make purchase CutWrappingPaper() Measure box Take out scissors Snip snip FitToGift() If fuzzy sweater, then… If bottle of wine, then… FastenWithTape()  If we write that code 100 times, it is time-consuming, error-prone and requires no use of our noggins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Googlebot runs Javascript</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-googlebot-runs-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-googlebot-runs-javascript/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had idle chats with techie friends wondering whether search engines such as Google simply index the raw HTML of your web page, or do they actually parse and “display” it as a true browser would.
I’ve generally believed they must be doing the latter. These days, a lot of a page’s content may be generated by Javascript and therefore would not appear in the raw HTML as served by the web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings are error states</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/meetings-are-error-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/meetings-are-error-states/</guid>
      <description>Paul Graham explores the difference between the maker’s schedule and the manager’s schedule. People that know me have heard me say that “meetings are the opposite of work”. Paul offers empathy: When you’re operating on the maker’s schedule, meetings are a disaster. A single meeting can blow a whole afternoon, by breaking it into two pieces each too small to do anything hard in. Plus you have to remember to go to the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making good programmers feel like bad programmers</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/making-good-programmers-feel-like-bad-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 11:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/making-good-programmers-feel-like-bad-programmers/</guid>
      <description>A web developer friend of mine has been doing a lot of backend-integration-type work over the last year, and has therefore has not been developing web sites. He made a point of wading back in to the web this week, so as not to get too “rusty”, in his words.
He is working in ASP.net Web Forms — and the wading did not go well. He is struggling to do what he considers basic stuff like toggling between an edit form and a detail view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to tell the new Intel SSDs from the old ones</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/how-to-tell-the-new-intel-ssds-from-the-old-ones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 21:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/how-to-tell-the-new-intel-ssds-from-the-old-ones/</guid>
      <description>Intel today announced faster and cheaper versions of their very impressive solid state hard drives (SSDs). I didn’t see any ship dates so I guess they are making their way into the sales channel now.
Since the new ones and the old ones share the X25-M model name, you’ll want to know which one you are getting.
To get the new ones, you’ll want to look for a “G2” at the end of the model name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Known and unknown unknowns</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/known-and-unknown-unknowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 13:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/known-and-unknown-unknowns/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Atwood has an article revealing some things that I’ve learned about software and business in general: the dangerous belief in certainty.
Software is unique in that solved problems are easy to build on. Once a problem is considered “solved”, the solution can be exploited with little or no cost. (When’s the last time you worried about the TCP/IP stack when building a web app?)
Therefore, if a software developer is asked to create something new, she is in all likelihood solving a problem that has not been solved before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the VP of Monetizing Synergy off today?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/is-the-vp-of-monetizing-synergy-off-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/is-the-vp-of-monetizing-synergy-off-today/</guid>
      <description>So, I’m a bit surprised that the upcoming Web version of Office isn’t based on Silverlight (Microsoft’s “rich internet application” framework). Instead, it appears that it will be browser-native, which is to say, written in Javascript.
From a Microsoft corporate perspective, this seems like it would be a perfect opportunity to promote Silverlight. As a relatively new platform, Silverlight’s biggest challenge is getting a widespread installed base. There will presumably be millions of people who wish to use the Web version of Office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps goes physical, Gavin Newsom doing product endorsements</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/google-maps-goes-physical-gavin-newsom-doing-product-endorsements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 10:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/google-maps-goes-physical-gavin-newsom-doing-product-endorsements/</guid>
      <description>Walking to my client’s place this morning, I couldn’t help but wonder what-the-hell-is-that? as I approached the cafe:
Looking more closely…
So Google is doing physical, even 3-dimensional advertising here in SF. Nicely done.
But should we be concerned that Gavin Newsom — SF mayor and California gubernatorial candidate — is endorsing a product?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy licensing costs, MasterCard</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/holy-licensing-costs-mastercard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 20:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/holy-licensing-costs-mastercard/</guid>
      <description>In one commercial, you’ll see Marlon Brando, Carols Santana, Marilyn Monroe and the Ramones, with a David Bowie tune in the background:
youtube [http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iQp8lzikSsU&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0]
Usually you get derivatives “in the style” of those sorts of artists, on the cheap. I wonder what MasterCard paid for all that stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript is now strategic for Microsoft</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/javascript-is-now-strategic-for-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/javascript-is-now-strategic-for-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>In this video, Chris Bryant of Microsoft makes an offhand comment that the components of the new Microsoft Office 2010 for Web are “some of the biggest Javascript applications ever built”.
The Javascript performance in Internet Explorer generally lags behind that of its competitors (Firefox, Safari, Chrome) — though the importance to the end user experience is debatable. IE has made strides, but the others have improved performance by orders of magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscription media consolidation gets started</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/subscription-media-consolidation-gets-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/subscription-media-consolidation-gets-started/</guid>
      <description>There are rumors that Amazon is interested in buying Netflix. I like the idea, though it’s just one step toward the sort of subscription media consolidation that I outlined a while ago.
What Netflix offers Amazon is a highly-regarded service and a substantial audience. This is also known as a brand.
What Amazon offers Netflix is scale and a future. While Netflix is king of the heap in the DVD rental business right now, their future as a streaming company is anything but assured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandora’s trying to change my tastes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/pandoras-trying-to-change-my-tastes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 16:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/pandoras-trying-to-change-my-tastes/</guid>
      <description>I got nothing against Jon Secada, but that ain’t what I’m listening to, Pandora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone needs multi-tasking, stat</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-iphone-needs-multitasking-stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 23:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-iphone-needs-multitasking-stat/</guid>
      <description>Joshua Topolsky offers a very funny and insightful take on the iPhone’s very fundamental flaw: it is designed for doing one thing at a time. […] my work requires that I use a bunch of web tools, look at lots of news sites, and have a feed reader open… basically, things that would require some level of multitasking. Imagine the frustration of having to constantly break the connection in chat to go look at a site or work on a post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Wolfram Alpha too clever by half?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/is-wolfram-alpha-too-clever-by-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/is-wolfram-alpha-too-clever-by-half/</guid>
      <description>An excellent and exhaustive survey of Wolfram Alpha by Mencius Moldbug. I think he thinks like I do: an engineer that looks at user interface analytically.
That’s not as bad as it sounds. I have no visual design abilities myself, yet I know something about interface. It has to do with expectations.
MM’s critique is that Wolfram Alpha is a great tool with a fundamental mistake in its interface. The mistake is that it makes a promise it can’t achieve: For serious UI geeks, one way to see an intelligent control interface is as a false affordance — like a knob that cannot be turned, or a chair that cannot be sat in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A prediction of EU hypocrisy</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/a-prediction-of-eu-hypocrisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 23:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/a-prediction-of-eu-hypocrisy/</guid>
      <description>Google’s search market share in Europe is over 80%. Meanwhile, Microsoft’s Internet Explorer — the target of repeated anti-trust charges by the EU — hovers under 50% in Europe.
By creating an operating system, it seems that Google is doing what monopolists are prohibited from doing: extending its dominance from one market to another. (Of course, Google’s new OS doesn’t exist yet and won’t have substantial market share for several years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Google Chrome OS get traction?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/can-google-chrome-os-get-traction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 22:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/can-google-chrome-os-get-traction/</guid>
      <description>Google has pre-announced the “Google Chrome OS”. It’s intended as a lightweight operating system built primarily for hosting a browser.
The post is short on specifics, mostly mentioning goals. I think it sounds very attractive — I only write web apps these days and know very few people who don’t. But will it get traction?
I think out of the gate, it will be slow going. After all, if you (as a user) want to live on the web, you have that ability now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new wave of self-shorteners</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-new-wave-of-selfshorteners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 21:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-new-wave-of-selfshorteners/</guid>
      <description>So, my previous bit on the attraction of shortening one’s own URLs seems to have some traction. Obviously it wasn’t original to me, but I see that sites like Ars Technica and Flickr have begun doing their own URL shortening. Check it out:
http://arst.ch/4fj
I had a similar notion a few weeks ago. In addition to shortening one’s own URLs, one might even use a shorter domain name that evokes the full name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is a Social Security Number considered a secret?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/why-is-a-social-security-number-considered-a-secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/why-is-a-social-security-number-considered-a-secret/</guid>
      <description>Identity theft boggles my mind a bit. It’s no mystery why criminal enterprises attempt it. It’s a mystery that we have systems where public information is used for security.
The biggest one is your Social Security Number. Why should knowledge of a person’s SSN entitle you to anything? The SSN is a user ID. A public key at best. It is certainly not a password.
And yet we use it as such.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use case: the metric system, or, all that useless beauty</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/use-case-the-metric-system-or-all-that-useless-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 12:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/use-case-the-metric-system-or-all-that-useless-beauty/</guid>
      <description>Ah, nothing gets international rivalry boiling like soccer football and the metric system. One wonders why the metric system hasn’t taken off here in the US. I posit this: it doesn’t offer any advantage to end users, ie, regular citizens. Let’s do the use case.
Proponents of the metric system argue that it’s utterly logical. And it is; everything is decimal (base 10), so we can easily convert from grams to kilograms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More about {less}</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/more-about-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/more-about-less/</guid>
      <description>Raena Jackson Armitage offers an interesting exploration of LessCSS: I have a confession: I think parts of CSS suck. It’s repetitive, tedious, and … well, kind of dumb.
(Here are my previous comments.)
I wonder what it would take to work LESS into the CSS standard? The syntax seems intuitive and unambiguous, and feels like CSS. It’s a small evolution that would make a lot of people happy. I suspect the standards process is not so nimble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain names are too cheap</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/domain-names-are-too-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/domain-names-are-too-cheap/</guid>
      <description>I am not sure I’ve ever used the term “cyber” for anything, ever, but that’s the name given to those who squat on domain names. Here’s my story.
I am working on a startup and we are working to choose a name. We are lucky enough to have a friend who does naming professionally — that’s right — and she gave us a brainstormed list of 80+ possibilities. We picked our favorites and began polling our friends on their impressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday suggestion</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/birthday-suggestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 00:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/birthday-suggestion/</guid>
      <description>My birthday is in December, just sayin’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network, network, network, network or network?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/network-network-network-network-or-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/network-network-network-network-or-network/</guid>
      <description>I love how Vista offers me so many choices in getting on the interwebs. I can:
 Connect to a network Manage wireless networks Set up a connection or network Manage network connections  I can do this by first going to Network and Internet, and then to the Network and Sharing Center. So far, there are 6 “network” places that might do what I need. There’s also a Network item in the Start Menu which is something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google as censor? Of course.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/google-as-censor-of-course./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 22:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/google-as-censor-of-course./</guid>
      <description>Daniel Indiviglio semi-condemns Google for its compliance with Chinese censorship laws. The “condemnation” is that they put profits before ethics. But that’s way too simplistic and strikes me as a bit insincere — as if we are shocked that Google is trying to make money.
Google is strategically smart to comply with the Chinese government, just as they comply with laws here in the US. Of course they are pursuing profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use case: SSL and email</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/use-case-ssl-and-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/use-case-ssl-and-email/</guid>
      <description>Interesting article in the NYT about using SSL for email. It’s an option for Gmail which I turned on some time ago.
Eric Schmidt mentions that the (potential) downside of SSL is performance — your computer and the email service need to encrypt and decrypt data for every operation. That’s work. But does it matter to humans?
Let’s do the use case: how do we use email? Of all the applications we use on the internet, I would argue that email is the least real-time of all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone activation servers overwhelmed?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/iphone-activation-servers-overwhelmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/iphone-activation-servers-overwhelmed/</guid>
      <description>I am upgrading my iPhone 3G to the 3.0 software but am getting this:
Anyone else?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagine CSS evolved as a programming language</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/imagine-css-evolved-as-a-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/imagine-css-evolved-as-a-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>I’ve gotten reasonably good with CSS, but I often find myself feeling that certain concepts are conflated or a bit ad hoc.
CSS does two separate things:
 Defines a set of visual attributes as a “style” Specifies the DOM elements to which those styles are to be applied  These are different ideas, IMHO. For example, I’d like to define a color palette in once place, and then apply it in different ways throughout in my style library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Built-in” jQuery (and how IE can get some dev cred)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/builtin-jquery-and-how-ie-can-get-some-dev-cred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/builtin-jquery-and-how-ie-can-get-some-dev-cred/</guid>
      <description>I’ve mentioned in the past that jQuery is an API as much as it is a set of functions. As syntaxes go, it’s very nice — consistent, logical, readable.
What are the chances that one of the browser makers will announce “native” support for jQuery in their next version? What would this even mean?
Well, for starters, I think it would mean that the jQuery selector syntax would be understood by the browser as a DOM query language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a “programmer”?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-is-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 01:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-is-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Phil Haack has a nice exploration of what it means to “program”. As long as I’ve been doing this — since the early 90’s — there has always been the promise that “programming” will go away. This usually takes the form of visual tools that offer the ability to drag-and-drop the logical chunks of your programs together.
This is to say, we are continually promised the holy grail of declarative programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>64-bitness: what it is and what it ain’t</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/64bitness-what-it-is-and-what-it-aint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/64bitness-what-it-is-and-what-it-aint/</guid>
      <description>Very interesting post from Rico Mariani on the why’s and why-not’s of doing 64-bit applications, specifically Visual Studio. It’s important to understand that Visual Studio is about manipulating code, not the data that your code will ultimately handle.
This implies that, in order to truly exploit 64-bit, your program itself would need to be 4 gigabytes in size or larger.
Photoshop will benefit from keeping a massive image file in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cloud! The cloud!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-cloud-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-cloud-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Everything in technology is an abstraction of something else. The browser is an abstraction, the keyboard is an abstraction, C# is an abstraction; they all sit on top of other things and hide the details, with the goal of making you productive. (And each of those layers is actually comprised of many substrata.)
An abstraction is successful when we no longer need to look under the covers. It takes a while to get to that point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More jQuery performance tips: 11 keystrokes buy you 10x</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/more-jquery-performance-tips-11-keystrokes-buy-you-10x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 11:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/more-jquery-performance-tips-11-keystrokes-buy-you-10x/</guid>
      <description>Dave Ward has a very extensive post (with benchmarks) on jQuery selector optimization. Really interesting stuff — the lesson is, the more specific your query, the faster it executes. The DOM is a data source, after all. He was able to achieve a 10x performance improvement by adding just 11 characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leopard : Snow Leopard :: Vista : Windows 7</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/leopard-snow-leopard-vista-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/leopard-snow-leopard-vista-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>I’m excited about the new announcements from Apple today. Can’t wait to update my iPhone to the 3.0 OS and use the bitchen ZipCar app.
But it’s amazing how thick with spin the announcements are. Paul Thurrott offers a snarky take, and he’s largely right.
Apple feels the needs to dis Windows 7 as a minor update to Vista. And yet, that’s precisely what Snow Leopard is — a minor update to Leopard, as evidenced by its upgrade pricing of $29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>URL shortener for ASP.net</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/url-shortener-for-asp.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 21:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/url-shortener-for-asp.net/</guid>
      <description>If you use Twitter, you are familiar with URL shortening services like bit.ly and tinyurl.com. They are useful for saving characters in the space-limited messages that Twitter allows.
However, in using them you lose control of your URL. End users don’t know what site they are going to before they click on it. Plus, your domain name is part of your brand — you want people to see it.
To remedy this, I’ve created a URL shortener for ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Live Writer works great with BlogEngine.Net</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/windows-live-writer-works-great-with-blogengine.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 21:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/windows-live-writer-works-great-with-blogengine.net/</guid>
      <description>Just experimenting a bit with using Windows Live Writer as a publishing tool for BlogEngine.Net. So far, it works really nicely. For one thing, it respects the theme of the blog right in the editing environment. Check it out:
That’s a local app you are looking at above, not this web site. After putting a screen shot in my post, it looks like a mirror reflecting a mirror. :)
The upside of using a local program for editing is faster saving of drafts plus nice conveniences like spell-checking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mayor at the movies</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/mayor-at-the-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/mayor-at-the-movies/</guid>
      <description>Ed Koch is doing movie reviews. What’s not to like?
blip.tv [http://blip.tv/play/g8s2gYbdKZfJDA]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OS still matters, or, platform abstraction is hard</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-os-still-matters-or-platform-abstraction-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-os-still-matters-or-platform-abstraction-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>Google has released some preliminary versions of Chrome for Mac and Linux. They announced it almost apologetically.
Writing a browser is way harder than anything I’ll ever try. Hats off to those making the effort.
But the difficulty and time it’s taking for Google to match their Windows version of Chrome speaks to the continuing importance of the OS. After all, the browser depends on the operating system for lots of stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highslide as ASP.net control</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/highslide-as-asp.net-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 21:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/highslide-as-asp.net-control/</guid>
      <description>Dave Ward has updated his ASP.net implementation of Highslide, a very nice ajax-y photo browser. I like the idea of encapsulating javascript into controls, btw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DOM is a data source, query it wisely</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-dom-is-a-data-source-query-it-wisely/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-dom-is-a-data-source-query-it-wisely/</guid>
      <description>Nice set of performance tips for jQuery selectors: http://www.artzstudio.com/2009/04/jquery-performance-rules/
They are all quite logical if you are used to selecting from data sets or file hierarchies. More specificity = faster selection; don’t do the same “query” twice.
Remember, the DOM is a data source. With an API as simple as jQuery’s, it’s easy to forget about the work being done underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GM &#43; Men’s Wearhouse = Tootsie Roll</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/gm-mens-wearhouse-tootsie-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/gm-mens-wearhouse-tootsie-roll/</guid>
      <description>For perspective, here are a few companies whose market cap is greater than GM:
 Cracker Barrel Papa John’s Men’s Wearhouse Rent-A-Center Earthlink Tootsie Roll  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying the Subversion revision number in your web application</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/displaying-the-subversion-revision-number-in-your-web-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/displaying-the-subversion-revision-number-in-your-web-application/</guid>
      <description>I found a nice technique for automatically displaying the SVN revision number in the footer of a web site. It is based in CruiseControl.Net.
Why would I do this? Well, we don’t have a strict version numbering convention for our app. We roll out incremental builds all the time. This falls under the technique of “continuous integration”, or in Google’s case, “eternal beta”. So it’s easier just to have the app give itself an incremental version number each time, that corresponds with our build process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New build of jQuery Controls [1.0.3433]</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/new-build-of-jquery-controls-1.0.3433/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/new-build-of-jquery-controls-1.0.3433/</guid>
      <description>There’s a new build of my ASP.net jQuery Controls, with a couple of conveniences. Details are in the Version History.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can haz Mifi?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/can-haz-mifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/can-haz-mifi/</guid>
      <description>This portable 3G-to-Wifi hotspot looks really great. Apparently Verizon and Sprint will offer it. The size is amazing — they claim it’s equivalent to “8 stacked credit cards”. (I am a bit shocked that no one has used the brand “MiFi” before!)
As with all things portable, battery life is the limiting factor. Only about 4 hours of active usage. A bit of research shows that you can power it from the wall or from your laptop USB to get a bit more time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New build of jQuery Controls [1.0.3429]</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/new-build-of-jquery-controls-1.0.3429/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/new-build-of-jquery-controls-1.0.3429/</guid>
      <description>There’s a new build of my ASP.net jQuery Controls, adding the ability to use server-side control ID’s in selectors. Download is here, version history is here. Gimme feedback here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javastrict</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/javastrict/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/javastrict/</guid>
      <description>John Resig (jQuery guy) talks about advances in the next rev of Javascript (properly known as ECMAScript 5). It now has a “strict” mode, which makes Javascript look a lot more like a compiled language.
When I first moved from classic ASP — interpreted VBScript — to C# in .Net, I must admit I was a bit annoyed. Why do I need to declare every variable? What’s this “build” stuff? I was used to just throwing text files on the server and if they were broken, I would hear about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscription music consolidation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/subscription-music-consolidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 13:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/subscription-music-consolidation/</guid>
      <description>I am a fan of subscription music services. I consider music a service, not a product. I am not interested in keeping track of what I own and where it’s stored. What I want is to queue up my tracks when and where I please — I don’t need to “own” anything to achieve that.
So I am a Rhapsody subscriber (after the Yahoo subscription service folded). The service is fine, but the user experience needs an overhaul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go craigslist</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/go-craigslist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/go-craigslist/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know what declaratory relief is, but clearly craigslist is on the right side of this argument. I am tempted to hire a South Carolinian hooker out of principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philip Greenspun…</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/philip-greenspun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/philip-greenspun/</guid>
      <description>…is someone I hadn’t heard of until I read this very amusing post: Ruby on Rails and the importance of being stupid. The comments are every bit as interesting as the article.
I like his economic thinking too, with obligatory reference to the excellent The Forgotten Man, which I am now “reading” (ie, glancing at, half-finished, on my desk).
I was a physics major, not a computer science guy. Turns out physics is great training for the problem-solving that programmers do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educator extension for BlogEngine.net released</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/educator-extension-for-blogengine.net-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 14:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/educator-extension-for-blogengine.net-released/</guid>
      <description>I’ve created an extension for BlogEngine.Net to improve typography. It “educates” the text, so that quotes and apostrophes are transformed into their smart (curly) counterparts. This blog uses it.
It’s called Educator and details are here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden features of C#</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/hidden-features-of-c-sharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/hidden-features-of-c-sharp/</guid>
      <description>I just came across this, many nuggets:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does null ever equal anything?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/does-null-ever-equal-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/does-null-ever-equal-anything/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday’s discussion of nulls got me to thinking about this common bit of syntax in C#:
[code:c#]if (myObject == null)
{
…
[/code]
But here’s the thing: null is not data. It’s metadata. That is, it describes the state of a variable, not its contents.
Null indicates the absence of a value. So the above code says, is myObject’s value equal to not having a value? Seems strange.
Other languages seem to make this distinction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nulls and knowledge</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/nulls-and-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/nulls-and-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Eric Lippert has a worthwhile post about what nulls are and why we use them. I like reading Eric because I think we think alike — computer languages are languages, with grammar and semantics.
Thinking this way allows one to design architectures that are intuitive. After all, when you create an object model, you are effectively creating a domain-specific language. Even it it’s written in C#, GetWidgets() is only meaningful within your business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox has a user base; does it have a future?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/firefox-has-a-user-base-does-it-have-a-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2009 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/firefox-has-a-user-base-does-it-have-a-future/</guid>
      <description>Firefox is a fine browser. Really, the current release of any of the major browsers is very good.
Firefox is currently, and comfortably, the #2 browser in market share. A look at the competitive landscape makes me wonder, however, if they have an audience in the long term.
There are probably two kinds of web users — those who make deliberate decisions about browsers and those who don’t. I think both will have less reason to use FF as time goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery controls alpha available for download</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/jquery-controls-alpha-available-for-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 08:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/jquery-controls-alpha-available-for-download/</guid>
      <description>I’ve made an alpha version of my jQuery controls available for download. I hope you will give them a try and let me know your thoughts. Comment here or hit me at matt at clipperhouse.com. Cheers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebClient, Fiddler and SSL</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/webclient-fiddler-and-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/webclient-fiddler-and-ssl/</guid>
      <description>I am developing a credit card authorization library which uses the WebClient class. In addition, I am using the excellent Fiddler to watch the requests and responses.
As you might expect, the credit card web service is HTTPS. Fiddler is acting as a proxy server on my dev machine.
Not surprisingly, WebClient throws an exception: “The underlying connection was closed: Could not establish secure channel for SSL/TLS”. As well it should — the SSL certificate in this case is not the one supplied by credit card authorizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hammering the DOM</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/hammering-the-dom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/hammering-the-dom/</guid>
      <description>As I work on my ASP.net jQuery controls, I got to thinking about what “animations” really are. The core animation framework in jQuery (as far as I can tell) is to simply iterate in small steps between two CSS states. So if you are going from 0% opacity to 100% opacity, jQuery applies (say) 100 CSS changes in 1% increments.
This is essentially hammering the DOM. The browser is forced to make 100 updates to the state of an element, and re-render it, over a short period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just getting started</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/just-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/just-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to ClipperHouse.com. It’s a place for my work and thoughts and stuff. There are lots of blank spots but you’ll see them filled in soon. Feel free to get in touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free shipping: getting closer</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/free-shipping-getting-closer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 04:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/free-shipping-getting-closer/</guid>
      <description>Public Knowledge points out AT&amp;amp;T’s new Terms which give different treatment to video based on its source. (No, it’s not neutral but of course, I think that’s fine.)
What right now looks like preferential economic treatment to an incumbent’s preferred bits is in fact setting the stage for putting such treatment up for sale. Mind you, the network won’t treat, say, iTunes’ actual bits any differently than anyone else’s. They’ll get delivered just like they are now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The long game on metered pricing: free shipping</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-long-game-on-metered-pricing-free-shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 17:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-long-game-on-metered-pricing-free-shipping/</guid>
      <description>Time-Warner cable has begun to roll out its metered pricing plan in Beaumont, Texas. Alley Insider says it won’t work, and Mike Arrington declares it a moral outrage. Both are missing the “third way” which I wrote about earlier this year.
Tying consumers’ prices to their consumption is not inherently a bad thing — in fact, it’s probably good for network buildout. Relating usage to fees provides a return on investment: more bandwidth provided equals more revenue, thus more capacity equals more revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The biggest threat to your rights? Scarcity.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-biggest-threat-to-your-rights-scarcity./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 06:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-biggest-threat-to-your-rights-scarcity./</guid>
      <description>I would not have predicted this: The U.S. Federal Communications Commission (FCC) should allow broadband providers to manage their networks and slow “bandwidth hogs,” despite concerns that such practices arbitrarily target some customers, said a coalition of seven civil rights groups.Net neutrality rules for broadband providers would protect bandwidth hogs at the expense of other customers and civic organizations, said the coalition, which includes the National Black Chamber of Commerce, Latinos in Information Sciences and Technology Association, League of Rural Voters, and National Council of Women’s Organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somewhere in Brussels, some buggy whips need gilding</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/somewhere-in-brussels-some-buggy-whips-need-gilding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 22:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/somewhere-in-brussels-some-buggy-whips-need-gilding/</guid>
      <description>One might think we live in feudal times, what with an unelected bureaucrat being able to tax companies arbitrarily and retroactively. However, since it’s an “anti-trust” issue, the European Commission gets around calling it a tax or tariff, and thus can charge whatever the Commission decides. There is no rate schedule to adhere to, no trade agreements to abide. Didn’t we get past this kind of thing hundreds of years ago?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demand first, then supply</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/demand-first-then-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 19:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/demand-first-then-supply/</guid>
      <description>Paul Buchheit, whom I’ve never read prior, has a very nice article about what makes a successful company: You can take the smartest, most experienced, most connected, most brilliant people in the world and have them build the most stunningly designed and technically advanced product in the world, but if people don’t want it, then you will fail.This is roughly what happened with the Segway, for example. […]Even if you aren’t the smartest person around, and your product is kind of ugly and broken, you can still be very successful, if you just build the right product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrepeneurs vs bureacrats</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/entrepeneurs-vs-bureacrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2008 21:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/entrepeneurs-vs-bureacrats/</guid>
      <description>A great story about TJ Rodgers’ personal green revolution.
Rich: UN committees. Reach: entrepeneurs. Advantage: reach.
h/t Peter Robinson @ The Corner</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation, incumbency, haves and have-nots</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/regulation-incumbency-haves-and-havenots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 20:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/regulation-incumbency-haves-and-havenots/</guid>
      <description>When we talk about regulations, in housing or agriculture or the Internet, it is usually sold as being intended to protect some “little guy” — be it the “family farm” or the file sharer. The insight that is most lacking is that regulations often have the opposite effect, which is to weaken consumers, the poor, or the upstart competitor.
In other words, regulations aimed at Goliath too often hit David. Case in point is a new study in Seattle where housing regulations intended to “preserve character” have driven prices up dramatically: An intriguing new analysis by a University of Washington economics professor argues that home prices have, perhaps inadvertently, been driven up $200,000 by good intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What advertising means</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-advertising-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 22:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-advertising-means/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I see a new ad for a product or industry, I am relieved and encouraged. Why? Isn’t advertising the most crass, manipulative expression of our capitalist system?
Yes. But more than that, it is a plea to the consumer. And this is a good thing.
You see, when a company advertises, it indicates that they need us. That they have reason to plead their case directly to the consumers, aka the individual citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast on broadband with your humble host</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/podcast-on-broadband-with-your-humble-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 22:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/podcast-on-broadband-with-your-humble-host/</guid>
      <description>The good folks at Technology Liberation Front asked me on to discuss the ideas behind this post, broadband policy and net neutrality. Be sure to grab someone you love, crack open a Colt .45 (“works every time”) and give a listen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet diversity &amp; cut cables</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/internet-diversity-cut-cables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 20:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/internet-diversity-cut-cables/</guid>
      <description>Internet diversity &amp;amp; cut cables Following on to my previous post that multiple broadband strategies are better than a single one, we’ve been hearing quite a bit about cut cables in the Middle East and India. While not perfectly analagous to our domestic infrastructure, these events point out a fundamental quality of the Internet: diversity.
While it’s easy to suppose that a “national broadband strategy” is desirable, in fact it is likely to make the Internet less diverse in terms of infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we have are multiple broadband strategies; this is a good thing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/what-we-have-are-multiple-broadband-strategies-this-is-a-good-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 20:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/what-we-have-are-multiple-broadband-strategies-this-is-a-good-thing/</guid>
      <description>Over at Ars, the normally reasonable Nate misses the point on a national broadband strategy. He despairs over the fact that “we”, meaning the government, have no broadband strategy.
Actually, in the US, we have numerous broadband strategies. Verizon’s strategy is fiber to the home. AT&amp;amp;T’s strategy is fiber to the node. Comcast’s strategy is DOCSIS 3.0. Sprint’s strategy is WiMax.
Each of these strategies is backed by highly incentivized companies, risking their own capital — not taxpayer’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The long game on metered pricing and Net Neutrality</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-long-game-on-metered-pricing-and-net-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 00:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-long-game-on-metered-pricing-and-net-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Time-Warner announced that it is experimenting with metered Internet pricing in a couple of markets. The same week, HBO (owned by TW) announced that it will be offering a number of its shows free over the Internet to existing HBO cable subscribers.
Ars Technica notices what seems to be a bit of a contradiction: on one side, TW are sending lots of new data down the pipe in the form of HBO shows, while on the other side they are making it more expensive for such high-bandwidth applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>